翻译：hardstick 校订：hardstick
影片情节源自真实事件
紫檀镇
紫檀镇第一非裔美国人卫理公会教堂
1922年12月31日，星期四，佛罗里达州紫檀镇。
J.布莱德利有5英亩土地出售，拍卖日期：1月1日。
普林斯·霍尔(Prince Hall)(约1735-1738-1807)，美国黑人废奴主义者，
波士顿自由黑人社区领袖。他创立了共济会王子堂(Prince Hall Freemasonry)，
并为非裔美国儿童的受教育权进行游说。他还积极参与了非洲回归运动。
霍尔试图为纽约被奴役和自由的黑人争取共济会、教育和军队的一席之地，
这些都是他那个时代最重要的社会领域。霍尔被认为是美国“黑人共济会”
的创始人，今天被称为Prince Hall共济会。
Good morning.
早上好。
Good morning,Sylvester.
早上好，西尔维斯特。
Morning, Mama.
早安，妈妈。
Good morning, Gertie.
早上好，格蒂。
Good morning, Aunt Sarah.
早上好，萨拉阿姨。
Don't run...
别跑...
with them eggs, Arnett!
小心鸡蛋，阿内特！
凯利家
Big Baby?
大宝贝？
Ma'am, Miss White?
夫人，怀特小姐？
Big Baby, come...
大宝贝，过来...
over here, please.
请到这来。
Morning, Miss White.
早上好，怀特小姐。
Morning. Would you run this over to Mr. Wright at the store?
早。你能把这个送到赖特先生的店里吗？
Yes, ma'am, Miss White.
好的夫人，怀特小姐。
Big Baby...
大宝贝...
Ma'am?
夫人？
The name is Wright.
他的名字叫赖特。
Yes, ma'am.
是的，夫人。
Mr. Wright,got your breakfast!
赖特先生，这是你的早餐！
Mr. Wright!
赖特先生！
Oh, Mr. Wright!
哦，赖特先生！
Mr. Wright,I got your breakfast!
赖特先生，我拿来了你的早餐！
Mr. Wright, I got your breakfast!
Stay where you are,Big Baby!
呆在那儿别动，大宝贝！
Stay where you are!
你就呆在那儿！
I'm coming!
我来了！
Mr. Wright! Mr. Wright,I got your... breakfast.
赖特先生！赖特先生，我带来了你的早餐。
A nice day, ain't it?
天气不错，对吧?
Y'all get on now.
你去忙你的吧。
That'll be two pennies, please.
请付两美分。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
Girl, you better...
姑娘，你最好...
go away from here.
离开这儿。
How's the family?
家人怎么办？
Morning, Miss Sarah.
早上好，萨拉小姐。
Morning, Mr. Bryce.
早上好，布莱斯先生。
Lovely day, ain't it?
多好的一天，是不是？
Ooh, that it is.
哦，就是。
You got that egg for me, boy?
你给我带鸡蛋来了吗？孩子。
Yes, sir.
是的，先生。
There you are.
给你。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
You're welcome.
不客气。
- Here you go, Mama.- All right.
-给你，奶奶。-好的。
All aboard!
都上车！
萨姆纳镇
Shoot.
开枪。
Shoot, for Christ sake!
开枪，天呐！
You little mullet!
你这个小磨蹭！
What, are you an Audubon fella? You a bird-watcher?
怎么，你是奥杜邦的拥趸吗？你是鸟类观察家吗？
（美国画家，博物学家）
Come on.
快来。
This is going to be the first boar you smoked yourself.
这将是你第一次亲自熏制野猪肉。
You know what them Seminole injuns say?
你听说过塞米诺印第安人的谚语吗？
You don't?
你没听说过？
They say you only supposed to kill what you gonna eat.
他们说：吃什么就杀什么。
They say it's a sin if you don't.
他们说，如果你不这样做，就是罪过。
Damn Seminole.
该死的塞米诺人。
Listen here.
听好了。
Don't want you around that colored boy no more.
我不想让你再和那个黑人男孩在一起。
Arnett?
阿内特？
Don't look right, my boy trailing around after a nigger.
这样不好，我的儿子，别再围着一个黑鬼转了。
But he Arnett.He's my friend.
但是阿内特，他是我的朋友。
That hurt?
疼吗？
No.
不疼。
Why you cryin'?
那你为什么哭？
I ain't crying.
我没在哭。
You'll be a man soon.I'll get you there.
你会成为一个男人的。我会帮你达到的。
Hey, Duke!
嘿，杜克！
Seen any niggers out here?
这里有看见什么黑鬼吗？
No, sir.
没有，长官。
Well, one escaped off the chain gang near State Road.
有一个罪犯在州界附近逃脱了。
Name's Jesse Hunter.
名字叫詹姆斯.亨特。
He might have headed for Rosewood.
他可能会逃往紫檀镇。
You keep an eye out.
你注意观察。
You see him,don't shoot him.
如你看见他，先不要开枪。
Bring him to me.
带他来见我。
All right. Yes, sir.
好的，遵命，长官。
I say shoot him.
我说了，可以开枪。
Drive.
开车。
Aunt Sarah!
萨拉阿姨！
Sheriff.
治安官。
Morning.
早上好。
I got a surprise for you.
我有个惊喜给你。
- I wonder what it is.- Don't move.
-我想知道是什么。 -别动。
Come on, baby. Stop it.
算了吧，宝贝，停下。
James, come on now.
詹姆斯，算了吧。
Don't act like a child.
别像个孩子似的。
Fanny. Fanny.
范妮。范妮。
Stop it now.
快停下来。
Stop it.
停下。
Oh, Fanny.
哦，范妮。
I said stop it.Go to work.
我说了，别干了，回去工作。
Damn!
该死！
Morning, Sarah.
早上好，萨拉。
Morning, Mr. Taylor.
早上好，泰勒先生。
Floors need scrubbin',Aunt Sarah.
地板需要擦洗了，萨拉阿姨。
Relax, child. We already done scrubbed all the cypress...
放心吧,孩子。这老屋子外头所有的柏树…
out of these old boards.
我都会擦洗干净的。
Watch out!
小心！
Excuse me, Mr. Taylor.
对不起，泰勒先生。
科摩尔父子木材加工厂
往左：萨姆纳镇， 往右：紫檀镇。
Goddamn.
该死的。
So he won't come around here, huh?
不是说，他不会来这里吗？
Earl, put the gun away.
厄尔，把枪收起来。
Hell, that boy ain't no more off a chain gang...
见鬼，即使我是佛罗里达州长...
than I'm governor of Florida.
那小子也不可能是逃犯。
Sit on down.
坐下。
Bye, Emmett.
回头见，艾默特。
All right, settle down.
好了，都安静下来。
I'm gonna tell you a story, OK? Pay attention.
我要给你们讲个故事，注意听，好吗？
"Once upon a time,
“从前，
"there was a pony named Dark...
“有一匹名叫小黑的矮种马...
"who every night took little people to Sleepy Town.
“他每天晚上驮着小孩子们去往瞌睡城。
"One night, as Dark Pony started off,
“一天夜里，就在小黑又要启程的时候哦，
"he met a little boy named Naughty who called out...
“他遇见了一名叫小淘气的男孩子...
"Please let me go.
“请带我走。
"So Dark Pony whoaed...
“于是小黑吁吁着...
"and Naughty hopped on his back...
“而小淘气爬到了他的背上...
"and away they went.
“于是他们就出发了。
"They went galloping..."
“他们奔跑了起来...”
- Who's that? - I don't know.
-那是谁？-我不知道。
Hey, Cousin Scrappie.
嘿，斯卡比表姐。
Mr. Carter!
卡特先生！
You got yourself a customer!
你有客人来了！
Hey, mister,
嘿，先生，
why ain't you got a car?
为什么你不开车来？
I like a horse.
我喜欢这匹马。
Car's faster.
还是开车快。
I ain't in no hurry.You got a name, boy?
我又不着急。你叫什么名字，孩子？
Yes, sir. Name's Arnett.
先生，我的名字叫阿内特。
Booker T., meet Arnett.
布克.T.，这孩子叫阿内特。
Arnett, this here Booker T.
阿内特，这是我的马，它叫布克.T。
Why ain't you in school, boy?
孩子，你为什么不去上课？
I'm workin' for Miss Fanny Taylor.
我在为范妮.泰勒小姐干活。
She payin' you to follow me around?
她花钱让你跟着我吗？
Can I help you, mister?
我能帮你吗？先生？
Horse threw a shoe.Need all four done.
马踢掉了一个蹄铁，就要再换四个。
Hell, can't get to it till tomorrow.
见鬼，不能等到明天吗？
Closing early tonight.
天快黑了。
Why so?
为什么不做了？
It's New Year's Eve, sir.
今天是新年前夜，先生
Dance tonight,8:00, Mason Hall.
今晚有舞会，8：00在共济会大厅。
Put that horse in the stable.I'll take care of him for you.
把那匹马关进马厩。我会替你照顾他的。
That's a pretty horse, sir.
那马非常可爱，先生。
Thank you.
谢谢你了。
Now, Lemuel,you know me, I'm fair.
现在，莱缪尔，你了解我，我是很公平的。
I charge a dollar a jug.
我是按每罐一美元卖的。
But since you're into me for $12 already,
既然你已经欠了我12美元，
I'm going to have to put you down for three.
我得卖你三美元了。
Three dollars?
三美元？
Oh, now, Mr. Wright,that ain't fair.
噢，赖特先生，这不公平。
I... I know I owes you a lots,
我...我知道我欠你很多，
but I'm a regular customer.
但我是老主顾了。
One dollar.
一美元。
Thank you, Mr. Wright.
谢谢你，赖特先生。
You better stop drinking, Lemuel,
你最好别再喝酒了，莱缪尔，
before I own... your house.
要不我就要拥有...你的房子了。
Free of charge.
这个是免费的。
Go see after your father.
去看看你父亲。
Thank you, Mr. Wright.
谢谢你，赖特先生。
Future customer.
未来的主顾。
Sorry, I don't extend credit to strangers.
对不起，我不给陌生人赊账。
You own that plot of land across the way?
对面的那块地是你的吗？
I will...
我将会拥有的...
this time tomorrow.
在明天这个时候。
Look at this,all these melons, no good.
你看，种的全是甜瓜，一点儿用处都没有。
Spoiled. Hog food now.
又不能吃。还不如拿来养猪。
Jewel, darlin',you got to throw these out.
朱厄尔，亲爱的，你把这些扔出去。
You got some.45 shells?
你有点45的子弹吗？
Clean out.
卖光了。
Be going to Gainesville first thing in the morning.
明早第一件事就是去盖恩斯维尔。
I'll pick some up.You still be around then?
我去进一些货。如果那时你还在的话？
Might be.
也许吧。
What's wrong with you two today?
你们两个今天是怎么回事？
Every time I try to tell you to do something,
每次我想让你俩做什么，
you won't listen.
你们都不听。
You know, I will smack you.I'll smack you.
听着，我要揍们。
No more playtime for you, none.Not today.
别再求我，今天不管用。
Mornin', teacher, ma'am.
早上好，老师，夫人。
I wonder if you can tell me...
你能告诉我...
where a man can find hisself a good meal?
哪儿有饭吃？
Y'all go inside.
你俩进屋去。
Well, my name ain't "teacher, ma'am." It's Beulah.
我的名字不叫“老师，夫人”，我叫比乌拉。
Folks I know call me Scrappie.
认识我的人叫我“斯卡比”。
Well, folks I know call me Mann...
那好，认识我的人叫我“曼恩...”
Miss Scrappie.
斯卡比小姐。
Nice to meet you, Mr. Mann.
很高兴认识你，曼恩先生。
Likewise.
我也是。
Now, this here Rattler,Mr. Mann.
曼恩先生，它叫“响尾蛇”。
He a deer dog.
他是一条鹿犬。
He help me hunt,
他帮我打猎，
'cause he can get real quiet,know what I mean?
因为他很安静，明白我的意思吗?
All right, come on, boy.
好了，来吧，小子。
This way now. This way.
这边来，这边。
So, what, uh,
呃，那什么，
what you selling now,Mr. Mann?
你现在推销什么呢？曼恩先生。
What makes you think I'm selling something, Mr. Carrier?
你凭什么认为我在卖东西，开利先生？
Well, I figure a colored fellow with nowhere particular to be,
好吧，我想一个没有什么特殊身份的有色人种，
that man be sellin' something...
那他一定是在卖东西…
or he runnin'.
或者他在逃跑。
Well...
那么...
you figure wrong...
你搞错了...
friend.
交个朋友。
Come on inside.
进屋吧。
Hey, Gertie,got some good news.
嘿，葛蒂，有个好消息。
Mr. Mann here ain't sellin' nothin'.
曼恩先生什么也不推销。
Turn that music down.
把音乐声关小一点儿。
My husband got a suspicious mind.
我丈夫总是疑神疑鬼。
Oh, yes, I do.
哦，我是这样的。
He's sweet on you.
他看上你了。
Scrappie, come over here and help me with this bird.
斯卡比，过来帮我端出这只烤火鸡。
Must be New Year's.
一定是到了新年了。
Yes, sir.Come on in, Mr. Mann.
是的，先生。进来吧，曼恩先生。
Evenin', Mr. Mann.
晚上好，曼恩先生生。
Ma'am.
夫人。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
This is my brother James,
这是我的兄弟詹姆斯，
his wife Emma, and their daughter Jewel.
这是他的妻子，艾玛，还有他们的女儿，朱维尔。
Be quiet.
安静点儿。
Scrappie, show the man a seat.
斯卡比，为客人准备座位。
You can sit here.
你可以坐在这里。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
Scrappie!
斯卡比！
Now, I had a talk with Mr. Andrews...
跟你说，我今天和安德鲁斯先生谈了...
on your behalf today.
为了你的利益。
What about Mr. Andrews?
安德鲁斯先生怎么了？
Mama, that old cracker...
妈妈，我正撞见那个老坏蛋...
caught hisself whistling at Scrappie and all that.
冲着斯卡比吹口哨来着。
What?
什么？
Yeah, that's right.
是的，就是那样。
I went over there and gave him some words.
我过去跟他理论了几句。
Sylvester, what you say to them people now?
希尔维斯特，你现在想说什么？
Mr. Andrews, I come to have a word with you about my cousin.
安德鲁斯先生，我来跟你谈谈我表妹的事。
Now, I expect you to show her some respect.
从现在起，我希望你能尊重她。
You expect, boy?
小子，这就是你想的？
I don't like Scrappie feelin' scared around nobody.
我不喜欢斯卡比在别人面前感到害怕。
That a threat?
这是在威胁吗？
Ain't no threat needed.
不需要威胁。
I'm just sayin' I don't mess with your peoples,
我只是说，我不会惹你的人，
I don't want you messin' with mines.
我也不想你惹我的人。
Now, I thank you very kindly, sir.
现在，我认为你还是个很好的人，先生。
Sylvester, you can't talk to white folks like that...
希尔维斯特，你不能这样对白人说话...
and not expect a rope around your neck.
除非你想被绞死。
Look, times is changin', Mama.
你看，妈妈，时代已经变了。
Now, I ain't no sharecropper.
我不是佃农了。
I'm a music teacher.
我是个音乐教师。
Times ain't never changed for no crackers, boy.
那些坏蛋可没随着时代而改变，孩子。
Don't you forget they burned a colored man...
别忘了，他们去年夏天还烧死过一个黑人…
over in Wylie last summer for winking at a white woman.
就因为他在怀利镇，对一个白娘儿们抛了个媚眼儿。
Sure did.
真是这样的。
I know that, Mama,
那件事我知道，妈妈，
but it's all right for them to whistle at Scrappie?
但他们就可以对着斯卡比吹口哨吗？
No, that ain't right.
不，那样做也不对。
What do you think about all this business, Mr. Mann?
曼恩先生，你对这件事情怎么看？
Oh, that man ready to eat.
哦，让人家吃饭吧。
Would you like to say the blessing, Mr. Mann?
你想为我们念祝祷辞吗？曼恩先生。
No, ma'am.
不了，夫人。
I'll do it, Mama.I'll do it.
我来吧，妈妈。还是让我来吧。
Thank you for the bounty of our lives...
感谢你赐予我们生命...
and the blessings you've bestowed on us...
感谢你赐予我们...
at home and family.
我们家的每个人。
Can I have my yams now?
我现在可以吃番薯了吗？
Who wants ham?
谁想要火腿？
I want some yams.
我想要点儿番薯。
Scrappie,come eat a part of the bird...
斯卡比，过来分这只火鸡...
that went over the fence last.
它差点儿就飞过篱笆。
Well, at least ask him...all right, all right.
好吧，至少问问他…好吧，好吧。
Ma'am, I ain't had a supper like that in a long time.
夫人，我好久没吃过这样的晚餐了。
Thank you kindly.
谢谢你们的好意。
You're welcome.
你不用客气。
You been drifting long,Mr. Mann?
你已经漂泊很久了吧？曼恩先生。
Seem like forever.
似乎要一直这样了。
That ain't no kind of life for a man.
那不是男人该过的生活。
You get yourself a good piece of land,
你应该找块好地，
the right woman...
找个合适的女人…
a man can make a new start 'round here,
一个人可以在这里重新开始，
make something of hisself.
开始他自己的生活。
Ain't that right,Scrappie?
不是吗？斯卡比？
Well, Aunt Sarah think Rosewood colored folks' heaven on earth.
莎拉阿姨认为，紫檀镇是人间天堂。
Best place these old eyes ever seen.
这是我见过的最好的地方。
Colored folks own all the land around here.
这里所有的土地都是黑人的。
All the businesses, too,
所有的生意也是。
except for Mr. Johnny Wright's store,
除了约翰尼.赖特的杂货店，
and he a halfway decent white man,
他还是个正派的白人，
if there ever was such a thing.
如果真有这种事的话。
Most of us doin' better than them folks over in Sumner.
我们大多数人都比萨姆纳那边的人过得好。
You ever seen a place like Rosewood, Mr. Mann?
你见过紫檀镇这样的地方吗？曼恩先生？
No, ma'am.
没有，夫人。
"Well, we know how to get money when we need some," said Pecos.
佩科斯说:“当我们需要钱的时候，我们知道如何弄到钱。”
"All right," nodded Essex.
“好吧，”埃塞克斯点点头。
"That's fine.
“这很好。”
"But don't tell anybody I told you...
“但是别跟别人说,我告诉你的话...”
"or I'll cut off your ears."
"否则，我就割下你的耳朵。"
He's a tough character, Essex.
他可真是个狠角色，埃塞克斯。
"Well, cross my heart and hope you die,"
“好吧，我发誓，希望你死，”
replied Lightning fervently.
闪电热切地回答。
"Well, that's fine,"replied Essex.
“那么，这样很好，”埃塞克斯回答道。
"Now, go home and shut up."
“现在，回家去，很么都不许说。”
"Or lose your ears,"added Thunder.
“不然就丢了耳朵。”鸣雷补充道。
And that's it.Next chapter next week.
就是这样。下一章，下周再读。
I'm going up Sumner, buying a drink for some of the boys.
我要去萨姆纳，给几个小伙子买杯喝的。
John, I was thinking we might read aloud...
约翰，我想我们可以大声朗读…
from the Good Book tonight.
《圣经》里的故事。
It'll still be good tomorrow.
那就明天念吧。
All right, boys, up to bed.
好了，孩子们，上床睡觉。
Dad, come on.
爸爸，接着念吧。
Dad, could we please stay up just a few more minutes?
爸爸，我们还能再留一小会儿吗？
Best do what your ma says.
最好按你们妈妈说的去做。
She ain't my ma.
她不是我妈妈。
Timothy.
提摩西。
What'd you say?
你说什么？
What'd you say, Timothy?
你说了什么？提摩西？
What was that for?
这是为什么？
That's so you don't get to thinking like your brother.
这样，你才不会有你哥哥那样的想法。
Get on to bed now.
现在就上床睡觉。
Get on to bed!
睡觉去！
Sorry about that, Mary, love.
很遗憾发生了这个，玛丽，我亲爱的。
I guess the boys still miss her.
我想孩子们还在怀念他们的亲生母亲。
You do, too, I reckon.
我认为，你也有点儿。
You're damn right I miss her. Pardon me.
你说得对，我也想她。请原谅我。
Only natural. Only been gone 7 months... 7 months, 3 days.
这是自然的。才走了7个月…7个月零3天。
I'm going to that auction tomorrow.
我明天要去拍卖会。
Get that plot of land.
买下那块地。
Does that mean we're staying, then?
那就是说我们要留下了，然后呢？
Ain't no sense of moving away.
离开没有任何意义。
I get Bradley's 5 acres, build some bins out back, sell feed.
我得到布拉德利的五英亩地，在后院建一些货箱，卖饲料。
Make enough money, in a few years,
几年后，就能挣下不少钱，
we'll move to Gainesville,
我们将搬到盖恩斯维尔，
open a bigger store, biggest they ever seen in Florida.
开一家在佛罗里达最大的商店。
Did you ever consider how I feel living here?
你有没有想过，我住在这里是什么感觉？
Why don't you go on and have that drink?
你为什么不去喝一杯呢？
You be all right alone here New Year's?
你独自在家里过元旦，没事吗？
I got Jesus with me.
我有上帝陪伴我。
Go ahead.
去吧。
There he is.
他就在那儿。
Gertie looks good.
葛蒂看起来很好。
Watch yourself, there, Carter.
看你自己，那儿，卡特。
Watch yourself there.
看你自己。
I'm gonna cut a rug.
我要跳摇摆舞。
Cut a rug.
摇摆舞。
Go on, cut that rug, but don't cut it too deep.
继续，摇摆去吧，但别太嗨了。
Come on.
来吧。
Dance like he's riding Booker T.
像他骑着布克·T一样跳舞。
Twirl that man, Scrappie.
转晕那家伙，斯卡比。
Listen here, now.Y'all take notes, all right?
听到这里,现在。你们都应记笔记，对吧？
I don't want to have to do this more than once.
我不想再说第二遍了
Come on, man,show him how to do it.
来吧，哥们，教他们怎么做。
Sylvester can't do no dancing.
西尔韦斯特不跳舞就受不了。
Africa.
非洲。
Nigerian.
尼日利亚人。
星期五
My arm! My arm! My arm! My arm!
我的胳膊！我的胳膊！我的胳膊！
I got you. I got you.
我抓住你了。我抓住了你。
I... I brung you some coffee.
我...我给你拿来些咖啡。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
It's all right.
没关系的。
I shouldn't have snuck up on you.
我不该偷偷接近你的。
You ridin' out today?
你今天要出去吗？
I might be here a couple more days anyway.
我可能还要在这里呆几天。
Thinkin' about lookin' in on that piece of land over there.
想去看看那边的那块拍卖地。
Bye.
再见。
Mornin', Mr. Mann.
早上好，曼恩先生。
Mornin', boy.
早安，孩子。
Tomorrow's my birthday.You gonna come to my party?
明天是我的生日，记得要来参加聚会。
You gonna have cake?
你会有蛋糕吗？
Yes, sir, chocolate.
是的，先生，巧克力的。
Why is she skippin'?
她跑什么？
Good coffee.
很棒的咖啡。
Morning, Mr. Mann.
早上好，曼恩先生。
Small town, people talk.
这小镇子上，人们都说起了你。
Old hangover remedy.
这是解决宿醉的老偏方儿。
My granddaddy taught me.
我的爷爷教会我做的。
Here's to the new year.
今天就是新年了。
I'm sober now.
我现在清醒了。
You got some peaches?
你有桃子吗？
Story going around is you was over there in the big one.
听说你曾经在美国陆军第一师服役过。
How long you fight? Few months? A year?
你打过多长时间的仗？几个月？一年？
I'm a veteran myself, Navy.
我也是退伍老兵，我是海军。
Spanish-American War.
我参加过美西战争。
Of course, the ass we kicked only took one day.
当然了，我们只花了一天时间就打赢了。
Steamed into Manila Bay May 1, 1898,
aboard the gunboat Concord under old George Dewey.
乘坐康科德号战列舰驶入马尼拉湾。
Set them 8-inch guns a-blazing till smoke blotted out the sun.
让8英寸口径的大炮开火，直到烟雾遮住太阳。
Sunk the Spanish fleet,steamed out May 2.
击沉西班牙舰队，他们于5月2日撤离。
Only eight Americans got wounded.
只有8名美国人受伤。
I had the audacity to be one of them.
我有胆量成为他们中的一员，
Where were you? France?
你在哪里参战的？法国？
Put my foots in Germany, too.
我也踏足过德国。
Germany?
德国？
I'd like to see the Kaiser's face...
我真想去看看德皇的脸...
when you come runnin' out of the Black Forest.
当你们从黑森林中出现时。
We didn't have no coloreds on the Concord.
我们的康科德号上没有有色人种。
Whole ship full of good ol' boys.
整艘船都是好孩子。
Wouldn't have took to it.
你也许不喜欢这个。
Maybe.
可能吧。
The mortars start flyin',
迫击炮开始轰鸣
the gas start blowin',
硝烟弥漫，
there ain't much color in them trenches.
战壕里没有多少有色人种。
Is that right?
真的吗？
You got them.45s?
你有点45的手枪子弹吗？
.45s. Funny thing about the draft.
点45子弹。征兵处在开玩笑吧。
I can't understand it. Pull a colored boy out of his home,
我不明白。把一个黑人男孩从家里拉出来，
send him over there, tell him dig trenches, kill white folks.
派他上战场，告诉他挖战壕，杀白人。
That seem right to you?
你就是这样吧？
I wouldn't know much about that, sir.
我对此了解不多，先生。
I volunteered.
我是自愿参军的。
You been double-timing me.
你一直在敷衍我。
Seeing that married Miz Connelly over in Wylie.
看到那个在怀利的已婚妇女，米兹.康纳利吗？
I know.
我知道。
Where you going?
你要去哪里？
Back to work.
回去工作。
Don't you turn your back on me...
不许你背对着我...
when I talk!
尤其在我讲话时！
Damn swamp tramp!
骚娘们儿！
What you crying about?
你为什么哭？
What you think you're doing, hitting me?
你认为你在干什么？想打我吗？
You little swamp tramp!
你这个小骚货！
小骚逼！
Huh? You little chigger!
呃？你个小臭虫！
You don't hit me!
你别想打我！
别想打我！
You don't hit me!
你别想打我！
Girl...
丫头...
Get out! Get out!
滚出去！滚出去！
Get out!
滚！
Philomena!
费罗米娜！
M-Miz Taylor?
泰勒小姐？
Is you all right, ma'am?
你没事吗？夫人？
Go away, Philomena.
走开，费罗米娜。
B-But...
但，但是...
Get out.
出去。
Get out!
出去！
So you fight in the war?
那么说你打过仗？
Kill anybody over there?
在战场上杀过人吗？
I mostly dug trenches.
我主要是在挖战壕。
Still, it must've been grand seeing Chicago...
不过，能看到芝加哥一定很壮观…
and New York.
还能看到纽约。
Shoot, I ain't been nowhere but Rosewood,
我呀，连紫檀镇都没离开过，
Sumner, Cedar Key,
还有就是萨姆纳，雪松树，
three times to Gainesville.
我就去过盖恩斯维尔三趟。
Why you come back south?
你为什么来我们南方？
Maybe...
也许...
I was looking for Rosewood.
我和紫檀镇有缘。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
Well, how come you ain't never settled down before now?
那你怎么一直没安定下来呢？
I was married...
我结过婚...
once.
就一次。
My Aunt Sarah, she say I ask too many questions.
我的萨拉阿姨，她总说我爱问很多问题。
I'm sorry if...
我很抱歉，如果...
How old you be,Scrappie?
你多大了？斯卡比。
I'm 17.
我17了。
No man?
还没男人吧？
- No young ones?- No.
-也没有小孩吗？-没有啦。
I just take care of my little cousins, though.
我还在照看我的小表弟。
Come on.
来吧。
Where you going?
你去哪里？
What you think about this land here?
你觉得这块地怎么样？
Well, I...I likes it fine.
那么，我...我喜欢它，很好。
Mr. Wright...
但是，赖特先生...
He going to buy it, though. He buying up everything.
他想买下这块地。他要买下一切。
Maybe.
也许吧。
Hey, anybody!
嘿，有人在家吗！
Hey, boy!
嘿，孩子！
Yes, sir.
是的，先生。
You a traveling man?
你接待过路人吗？
Who asking, sir?
你在问谁？先生？
We gots to help him.
我们得去帮他。
He ain't our problem.
他不关我们的事。
He a Mason,took the oath, same as us.
他是共济会成员，宣过誓的，跟我们一样。
He's a white Mason.
他是白人共济会的。
Do you think he'd help you?
你认为他会帮助你吗？
Aaron, boy, I swear,
阿伦，孩子，我发誓，
sometimes you ain't got more sense than some of these horses.
有时候你还不如这些马有见识。
Now, I'm telling you...
现在，我告诉你...
that man...
那个人...
he ain't nothing but trouble.
他就是在找麻烦。
Yeah, well, let me tell you something.
好吧，让我告诉你。
See, I ain't no boy.
你看，我不是小孩子。
See, I's a man.
你看，我是个男人。
I's a Mason.
是个共济会成员。
What you be, Sam?
你看你这样，萨姆？
Everybody sit down.Let's get this done.
大家都坐下。让我们完成这事。
Bradley, you got the deed?
布莱德利，你的房契呢？
Uh, yes, sir, I do, Mr. Andrews.
是的，安德鲁斯先生，我带了。
No, no, boy,I haven't paid for it yet.
不，不，孩子，我还没付钱呢。
We got to sell it first.
我们得先把它卖掉。
Here. Give it here.Give it here, boy.
这儿，交到这儿来，孩子。
We gots here 5 acres in Rosewood...
我们要对紫檀镇的5英亩土地...
adjacent to Mr. Johnny Wright's store...
它靠近约翰尼.赖特先生的商店...
sold as is,cash only.
如约出售，只收现金。
Let's open up at $52 an acre.
让我们先以每亩52美元开价。
52, 52. Who'll give me 52 down front?
53, 53, 53 from Monroe.
54, 54, 54.
Who'll give me 54?
有谁出54元？
54, 54.
John Wright again.Thank you, John.
约翰.怀特又出价了。谢谢你，约翰。
55, 55.
55, anybody? Monroe, 55?
$54.
Going once,going twice...
一次，两次...
$55.
Boy, you know that's $55 for each acre?
伙计，你知道那是每英亩55美元吗？
That's damn near $300.
那就是共需近300美元。
Yes, sir, I do.
是的，先生，我知道。
Thank you kindly.
谢谢你的好意。
Cash?
现金？
Where's that nigger going to get that kind of money?
那个黑鬼从哪儿弄到那么多钱？
I have $55.
我有55美元。
Get back to work.
继续干活。
Afternoon, Miss Fanny.
下午好，范妮小姐。
Help!
救命！
Help me!
帮帮我！
Somebody please help me!
请来人帮帮我！
Somebody!
来人啊！
Help me!
救我！
Help!
Please!
求你们了！
Help me!
救我！
What's the matter, now?
出了什么事？
Please help me!
请帮我！
Help me!
救我！
What's going on? Fanny, what happened?
怎么回事？范妮，发生了什么？
Nigger.
那个黑人。
It was a nigger.
是个黑鬼。
What?
什么？
He broke in my house,
他闯进了我的房子，
and he beat me up.
还打了我。
It was a nigger! It was!
是个黑鬼干的！是的！
Sheriff! Sheriff!
治安官！治安官！
Here comes that boy again.
那个男孩又来了。
That would be Emmett.
一定又是艾默特。
Sheriff!
治安官！
Take a breath, boy.
喘口气再说，孩子。
What's the matter?
怎么回事？
Your daddy's still caught on fire again?
你爸爸又在点火了？
Fanny Taylor got herself beat by a nigra.
范妮.泰勒好像被一个黑人打了。
Oh, shit.
噢，混蛋。
Damn.
该死的。
Earl, that scatter gun loaded?
厄尔，那把散弹枪上膛了？
No.
没有。
Where the hell's my... my shells?
我的那些...该死的子弹放哪里啦？
Can't find my damn shells.
我找不见子弹了。
Here.
在这。
Go to the mill.Get James.
去木材厂，找詹姆斯。
Hold on!
等一下！
Keep this quiet before I get the whole story. Go.
在我知道真相之前，别声张。走。
- What's going on? - Mind your own damn business.
-发生了什么？-管好你自己的事。
Come on, boy.
走，孩子。
When I want you to do something...
当我想做什么事情的时候...
and I tell you to do it...
我会告诉你的...
Fanny Taylor's been raped by a nigger.
范妮·泰勒被一个黑鬼强奸了。
Go on out there and do that!
继续干你的活吧！
Hey, James, I need to talk to you.
嘿，詹姆斯，我有话跟你说。
Your wife's been beat and raped by a colored man.
你妻子被一个黑人殴打强奸了。
What the hell you talking about?
你他妈在说什么？
57.50.
$58.
58.50.
$60.
Boy, how you planning on paying $300?
孩子，你怎么筹划你那300美元？
You got a bagful of gold?
你难道有一袋金子吗？
Could be, sir.
也许吧，先生。
Henry...
亨利...
can't you see what this boy's doing?
你看不出这孩子在干什么吗?
He ain't going to buy nothing.
他什么也不会买。
He's just driving up the price for old Bradley.
他只是在抬高老布拉德利的身价。
Mr. Andrews, sir, I don't know that man.
安德鲁斯先生，我不认识那个人。
With all due respect, Mr. Wright...
恕我直言，赖特先生…
if that what you believe,
如果如你相信的那样，
maybe you should stop bidding.
也许你就该停止竞价。
You gonna let that nigger beat you, Johnny?
你想让那个黑鬼打垮你吗，约翰尼？
60 goddamn 50.
妈的，60.50元。
A nigger raped Fanny Taylor.
一个黑鬼强奸了范妮·泰勒。
Listen up.
听好了。
We got to call this off for now.
我们得暂时停止这一切。
What? I ain't going nowhere.I got a bid in.
什么？我他妈哪儿不去。我还要竞标呢。
We'll pick it up tomorrow at $60.50.
我们明天以60.5美元的价格来继续拍卖。
Let's get this done now.
让我们现在把这件事做完。
John, Fanny Taylor's been raped by a nigger.
约翰，范妮.泰勒被一个黑鬼强奸了。
My deed.
我的地契。
I'll lock up the deed.
我要把地契锁起来。
Boy, your name Jesse Hunter?
小子，你的名字是叫杰西.亨特吗？
No, sir.
不是，先生。
I suppose you can prove that?
我怀疑你，你能证明你自己吗？
Got my discharge, sir.
这是我的退伍证书，先生。
Just who do you think you are, boy?
你以为你是谁啊，小子？
With all due respect, Mr. Wright,
恕我直言，赖特先生，
long around this time tomorrow,
明天这个时候，
I expects to be your neighbor, sir.
我希望成为你的邻居，先生。
Welcome to Levy County, Mr. Mann.
欢迎你来到李维县，曼恩先生。
Get out of the way.Come on, back off, now.
别挡道。快，退后，马上。
Come on, come on, come on.
快点儿，快点儿，快点儿。
Jesus, Fanny.
上帝啊，范妮。
Who raped you?
谁强奸了你？
No, jeez, Ellis,I sure wasn't raped.
不，天呐，艾利斯，我肯定没被强奸。
I just got beat.
我只是被打了。
I was beat badly.
我只是被狠揍了一顿。
Badly.
真惨。
He was so big.
他是个大个头。
He's so black,that boy.
那个男孩子，是如此的黑。
She says she was raped.
她说她被强奸了。
Raped and beat.
即被强奸又被打了。
Shut up, y'all! Everybody go on out of here!
你们都闭嘴！所有人都出去！
Show's over!You heard me!
没什么好看的！你们听见我说的吗！
Go on home!
都回家去！
Go on!
走开！
Come on.
来吧。
Let's go in the house.
我们进屋里去。
It's OK.
这就好了
It's all right.
这就没事了。
It's OK. Come on! Give her some breathing space!
没事了，快点走开！给她点呼吸的空间！
Damn.
该死的。
Listen to me.
听我说。
We've known each other a long time, huh?
我们认识很久了，对吧？
I want you to think about this, now.
我希望你现在好好回想一下。
You tell me.
告诉我。
This is Ellis.You tell me the truth.
我是艾利斯。你告诉我真相。
Was it truly a colored that done this to you?
是不是真的有黑人对你施暴了？
Be sure, darling,that is all I'm saying.
放心，亲爱的，这就是我要说的。
Yes, he was colored.
是的，他是个有色人种。
He was a nigger,nigger, nigger!
他是一个黑鬼。黑鬼，黑鬼！
Jesus, angel,what happened?
仁慈的上帝啊，这都发生了什么？
You seen this boy, Sarah?
你看见那个男孩了吗？萨拉？
Ain't got to mess around. We got to do something about this.
没必要浪费时间。我们得做点什么。
No, Mr. Ellis.
没看见，艾利斯先生。
I ain't seen nothing.
我什么都没看见。
All right.
那好吧。
Hey, what y'all doing?
嘿，你们怎么了？
Miss Fanny... Miss Fanny Taylor,she got raped.
范妮小姐...范妮小姐，她被强奸了。
- And beat.- And she got beat,
-还被揍了。-她还挨了揍，
and she said it was a colored man.
还说是一名黑人干的。
But it was a cracker.I seen him.
那是个坏蛋。我看见他了。
Well, I guess now we're looking for a nigger convict,
那么，我们现在就要搜查那个黑鬼罪犯，
escaped yesterday off the chain gang near Wylie.
昨天他还在怀利附近越狱了。
Name is Jesse Hunter.
他名叫杰西.亨特。
Oh, good.Here are the hounds.
噢，那好。这是搜寻猎犬。
Take them all around back,pick up a scent.
带它们去后面去，识别气味。
Go on.
去吧。
You acting like you the leader of this here mob.
你表现的就像你是这群暴民的头儿。
I am the leader,and this ain't no mob!
我是头儿，但这帮人不是暴民！
We got him, boys.
俺们似乎找到他了，孩子们。
See where they're headed?
看清了它们要去哪里吗？
Y'all see where they're headed?
你们都看清了他们要去向何方吗？
Come on, boy.
来吧，孩子。
Shut up, y'all! They got a scent!
别说话！他们好像闻见了气味！
Hush.
嘘。
Go have a look.Y'all go that way.
去看一下，你们去那边。
He ain't done nothing!
他什么也没做！
What did the boy do?
我孩子做了什么？
Y'all be quiet! Be quiet!
你们都安静下来！安静！
Poly! Poly!
泼利！泼利！
Put that gun away!
把枪收起来！
- This is serious business.- Yes, sir.
-这是严肃的事儿。-是的，先生。
You got to tell me the truth, boy.
你要告诉我全部的真相，孩子。
Did you rape Fanny Taylor?
你是否强奸了范妮.泰勒？
- Rape? - No, sir! No!
-强奸？ -没有，先生！没有！
Do you know who did?
那你知道是谁干的吗？
I don't know nothing,Mr. Walker!
我什么都不知道，沃克先生！
You know who did!
你一定知道是谁！
Go!
带走！
My boy ain't done nothing!
我的儿子什么都没做！
Hey! Here comes old Johnny Wright.
嘿！老约翰尼.亨特来了。
Hello, Johnny.
你好，约翰尼。
Hey, Bobby.
你好，鲍比。
John.
约翰。
How's that new wife of yours working out?
你的新妻子怎么样了？
She's coming right along.
她正在逐渐适应。
Sorry about that auction, John.The boy bid.
约翰，拍卖会的事情，我很遗憾。那孩子出价了。
Yeah, a hell of a thing.What you got here?
是的，真见鬼。你们怎么在这儿？
Now we got a good one.
俺们找到了一个好东西。
That boy raped Fanny Taylor.
这个强奸范妮.泰勒的男孩。
Is that right?
是他吗？
We got us Aaron Carrier, John.
约翰，俺们抓住了阿伦.凯利。
Aaron Carrier?
阿伦.凯利？
Watch that gun, boy.
孩子，小心枪走火。
How you doing, Johnny?
约翰尼，你看该怎么办？
You got the wrong boy.
你们抓错人了。
Hate to tell you, Aaron Carrier wouldn't rape a fly.
我懒得跟你说，阿伦.凯利连个苍蝇都不会强奸。
Dogs led us straight to his house.
是猎犬引导我们去的他家。
You know the boy that did?
你确定是这孩子干的？
Nigger won't talk,either, John.
黑鬼不会招供的，约翰。
I know his family.
我知道他们家。
Let me talk to him.
让我来问他。
Yeah, hell, maybe you can get something out of him.
是啊，也许你能问出点什么来。
I sure as hell can't.
我是不能了。
Aaron, this is Mr. Wright.
阿伦，我是赖特先生。
You know something about all this?
这件事，你知道什么吗？
Duke, how's he supposed to talk
杜克，你这样勒着他
when you're choking him like that?
怎么还能让他说话？
Well, he don't need to talk, Johnny.
他不需要说话，约翰尼。
He need to hang from one of them trees over there.
他就要被吊死在那棵树上了。
Y'all think this is real funny?
你们都觉得这很好玩吗？
Hey, you would, too, if you was the one that sold me this rope.
嘿，要是俺告诉你，这条绳子是你卖我的，你也会的。
Good point, John.
问得好，约翰。
He's a good boy.
他是个好孩子。
He ain't done nothing.
他不会干坏事的。
Duke, don't hurt him.
杜克，别弄伤他。
Emmett, come on over here, boy.Hold onto this rope.
艾默特，到这儿来，孩子。抓住绳子。
There's a boy.
这孩子能干的。
You know this boy's family as well as I.
你和我一样，也都认识这孩子的家庭。
That's right.I do. I know.
这就对了。我知道我认识他家。
And you know he's a good boy.
而你也知道，他是个好孩子。
They're good people.They're good people,
他们是好人，他们都是好人，
but we got a dilemma here, John.
但是我们骑虎难下了，约翰。
We got a dilemma. I'm going to tell you what it is.
我们是骑虎难下。我告诉该怎么办。
Hounds don't lie.
猎犬不会说谎。
Be a man, now.
现在，你长大了。
You got to take that rope and snap, crack.
你抓住绳子，使劲一拉，啪的一下。
Can't lynch that boy, Ellis.Can't lynch him.
你不能私刑处置那个孩子，艾利斯。不能用私刑。
I ain't going to let nobody get hanged.
我不会让任何人被绞死的。
I ain't going to let it happen.It won't happen.
我不会让这种事发生的。它不会发生。
Now grab that rope.Come on, grab it.
现在抓住这绳子，来吧，抓住它。
About 4 summers ago,I went over to Chiefland.
大约4年前的夏天，我去了奇夫兰。
A colored boy over there was looking in the window...
那边有个黑人男孩正从窗户往里看…
at a white girl watching her take a bath.
他在偷看一个白人女孩洗澡。
Did he say something?
他说了什么没有？
No, he didn't.
没有，他没说什么。
Maybe he don't know nothing if he didn't say nothing.
如果他什么都不说，也许他什么都不知道。
You should have seen them go crazy on that boy.
你真该看看他们对那男孩的疯狂。
Beat him about half to death.
把他揍到半死。
Boy wouldn't stop screaming.
那男孩不停地尖叫。
We helped him to the railroad track. Number 7 come along...
我们把他放到的铁轨上。7号列车开了过来...
cut his head clean off.
把他的头给压碎了。
Niggers don't run around like a chicken.
黑鬼就不应该像小鸡那样乱跑。
Once that head's off,he's dead.
脑袋一掉，他就死定了。
S-Sam Carter.
萨-萨姆.卡特。
Sam Carter?
萨姆.卡特？
What about Sam Carter?
萨姆.卡特怎么了？
What about Sam?
萨姆怎么了？
Sam the blacksmith?
是那个铁匠萨姆吗？
Sam Carter raped Fanny Taylor?
是萨姆.卡特强奸了范妮.泰勒吗？
No.
不是。
A man. A Mason.
另一个人，一个共济会成员。
What man? Who you talking about?
什么人？你在说谁？
Sam took him in the wagon.
萨姆把他放在马车里。
We was holding the oath.
我们都是宣过誓的。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
String him up!
把他捆上！
This boy's under arrest!I'm taking him to jail!
这孩子现在被捕了！我要把他送进监狱！
We're going to string this boy up.
我们要把这孩子捆起来。
Oh, no, you ain't!
哦，你们不能这样！
All right, take the boy,but don't you let him go.
好吧，带走这孩子，但别让他跑了。
Hey, don't you worry about what I am or ain't going to do!
嘿，你不用担心我要做什么或不做什么！
You hear me, Poly?
你听见我说的了吗？波利？
- We're going to get Sam.- You get on out of here!
-我们要去找萨姆。-你们最好离开这儿！
Do you understand? You go do it!
你明白吗？你去做你的去！
Hey, listen to me.You go with them.
嘿，听我说，你看着他们。
Don't let them do nothing until I get there, you hear me?
在我到达之前别让他们做任何事，听到了吗？
You go, too.Ellis, you go.
你也跟着去吧，艾利斯。
I'll take old Aaron in.
我把他送回老阿伦那儿。
Them boys is all riled.
那些孩子都被激怒了。
Aaron, this is all your damn fault!
阿伦，这全都因为你！
You should've said something earlier!
你应该早点儿说实话！
Damn!
该死！
Carter! Carter!
卡特！卡特！
Hey, Booker T.
嘿，布克.T。
Up, boy. Up.
抬起来，孩子。抬起来。
Thank you, Mr. Wright.
谢谢你，赖特先生。
Sam, what you know about this Jesse Hunter, boy?
萨姆，你对杰西·亨特了解多少？小子？
I don't know nothing, Mr. Andrews!
我什么都不知道，安德鲁斯先生！
All niggers don't know nothing!Where's Jesse Hunter?
所有的黑鬼都不知道！杰西.亨特在哪里？
Mr. Purdy. Mr. Purdy.
帕迪先生。帕迪先生。
You a Mason.You got to believe me.
你也是共济会员。你应该相信我。
I don't know no Jesse Hunter!
我真的不知道杰西.亨特！
Yeah, you do,you damn nigger!
是的，你是个该死的黑鬼！
Come on, let him go!
算了吧，让他走吧！
Come on! Hold it! Come on!
行了！住手！差不多了！
He's not against you! Stop it! Stop it!
他不是针对你！你别管！别管！
You shut up and get away!
你闭嘴滚开！
Sam! Get up!
萨姆！起来！
Talk now!
快招了吧！
Talk to me, Sam!
跟我说，萨姆！
Talk to me.
跟我说。
Better say something.
你最好说点什么。
As...
如果...
as God is my witness,
如果上帝替我作证，
I don't know...
我也不知道...
Jesse Hunter.
杰西.亨特。
It was that drifter. That rich nigger from the auction!
是那个流浪汉。拍卖会上那个有钱的黑鬼
That big buck with the black horse,
那个骑着黑马的大个子，
is that him?
是不是他？
Come on, let him talk.
行了，让他说。
Damn you!
你们这帮该死的！
Look at me!
看着我！
Aaron told us you gave him a ride!
阿伦告诉我你带他走了！
Now you show me where you put him out!
现在你告诉我你把他放哪了！
Show me, Sam.I can get you out of here.
告诉我,萨姆。我可以带你离开这里。
Show me, boy.
告诉我，孩子。
You going to show me?
你要告诉我吗？
We going to string you up.
我们要把你捆起来。
Let's go. Get up.
我们走。起来。
If we don't pick up his trail where you say,
如果按你说的我们找不到他的踪迹，
you one dead black son of a bitch.
你这个黑鬼就死定了。
What you got, Earl?
厄尔，你看见什么了？
Nothing, Ellis.
什么都没有，艾利斯。
Nothing?
没有吗？
Y-you can kill me...
你可以杀了我…
but you all...
但你们...
you can't eat me.
不能吃了我。
You ain't no Seminole, boy.
孩子，你再也不是塞米诺人了？
Duke.
杜克。
Get back! Get back!
靠后！靠后！
Damn it, Duke!
该死的，杜克！
What'd you do that for?
你干嘛要这么做？
Goddamn, Duke.
该死的，杜克。
Dumb son of a bitch.
蠢货。
You could've killed me!
你差点杀了我！
He's sure dead.
他肯定死了。
He ain't dead.
他还没死。
Well, let's clean this mess up.
那么，让我们来收拾这烂摊子。
Hang him up in this tree over here.
把他吊在那棵树上。
OK, men, I've had enough of this!
够了，伙计们，我已经受够了！
I'm the law here,you hear me?
我是这里的法律，听见我说的了吗？
Let me in here!
让我在这儿！
Back off now!
现在请回避一下!
Let me in there!
让我在这儿！
Stop it, y'all! Stop it!
住手，你们全都住手！
A white woman was beat and raped...
一名白人妇女被打了还被强奸了...
by a colored boy!
就是这个黑人干的！
Now, you want to tell her husband, her children,
现在，你想告诉她的丈夫，她的孩子们，
that this boy don't have to pay for that?
这个男孩不用为此付出代价吗?
I'm supposed to uphold the law!
我应该维护法律！
Aw, law!
啊，法律！
Whose law, nigger law?
谁的法律？黑鬼的法律？
You wasn't nothing but a damn chicken farmer...
你不过是个养鸡的…
till they gave you that stupid badge!
直到他们发给你这个警徽！
You want to get re-elected?
你还想连任吗？
- Leave me alone! - Then leave it be!
-别管我！-就让这发生吧！
I got your watch,Sam Carter!
我拿到了你的表，萨姆.卡特！
I got your watch!
我拿到了你的怀表！
You're always so gentle.
你总是那么温柔。
Soft touch.
温柔的抚摸。
You treat me like I'm some kind of angel.
你让我感到我有点像是天使了。
You are an angel to me.
你就是我的天使。
I'm just a woman, James.
我只是一个女人，詹姆斯。
I'm just a woman.
我就是个女人。
Things are getting crazy out there, Fanny.
外面的情况越来越疯狂了，范妮。
They're likely to get worse.
情况可能会变得更糟。
Sam Carter's lynched already.
萨姆.卡特已经被处以私刑。
The blacksmith?
那个铁匠?
What'd he do?
他做什么了？
He give that nigger a ride.
他载了那黑鬼一程。
A ride?
载了一程？
Sam Carter?
萨姆.卡特？
I didn't know.
我不知道。
There's things that I ought to tell you.
有些事情我应该告诉你。
Evening, Mr. Taylor.
晚上好，泰勒先生。
With all that's going on and everything,
发生了这么多事，
we thought y'all could use some hot cooking.
我们觉得你们应该来点热菜。
Thank you kindly, ladies, but my wife ain't feeling too well.
谢谢你们，女士们，但我妻子身体不太舒服。
It's all right, James.
没事的，詹姆斯。
Evening, Miss Walker.
晚上好，沃克小姐。
Oh, Fanny...
噢，范妮...
you poor child.
可怜的孩子。
Oh, I brought you a quilt, too.
我还给你带了被子。
I brought you sweetbread.
我给你带了甜面包。
Don't you worry.That nigger going to be dead...
你别担心。在你吃完这块馅饼之前...
before you finish your pie, OK?
那个黑鬼会被处死的，放心吧？
Get a wagon.
备马车。
Now, me and Mr. Mann just cut Sam Carter out a damn tree.
我和曼恩先生刚把山姆·卡特从树上割断了下来。
Y'all hear me?
你们听见我说的了吗？
Dirty, low-down bastards...
那些肮脏下流的混蛋...
took my boy.
抓走了我的儿子。
They got my cousin Aaron over in jail.
他们把我的表弟阿伦抓进了监狱。
There's Sumner behind this business.
幕后的黑手就在萨姆纳。
They say it's for his own protection.
他们说这是为了保护他。
Now how that sound?
现在听上去会怎么样？
What we need to do, we need to pray. Now, dear Lord...
我们需要做的，就是祈祷。现在,亲爱的主啊…
I ain't in no praying mood,preacher.
我可没心情祈祷，牧师。
Now, what I want to know is right now,
现在，我想知道的是，
what y'all mens prepared to do if they run back here?
如果他们到这里来，你们准备怎么做?
Not if, Sylvester. When.
不是如果，希尔维斯特，是何时。
I'm goin' to shoot.
我就要开枪。
Come on, sit down now, Big Baby.
算了吧，坐下，大宝贝。
You by yourself there, Mr. Wright?
你就一个人来吗？赖特先生？
I am, Sylvester.
我就一个人，希尔维斯特。
Sylvester, them crackers so riled up,
希尔维斯特，他们被激怒了
we don't know what they going to do.
我们不知道他们会怎么做。
They don't know what they goin' to do.
他们不知道自己要做什么。
That's how a lynch mob be.
这就是暴民滥用私刑的方式。
Now, I say we send the women and children...
现在，要我说，我们把妇女儿童...
to Gainesville right now.
立即送到盖恩斯维尔去。
John, we can't go nowhere and leave that boy in jail.
约翰，我们不能把那孩子留在监狱里。
No! Them dirty bastards...
不行！他们是肮脏的混蛋...
can take my boy out of that jail...
会把我儿子劫持出监狱...
and hang him whenever they take a notion.
然后随便就把他吊死。
Don't worry about it, Uncle.
别着急，舅舅。
We ain't going nowhere.
我们哪也不去。
We ain't going nowhere, Bradley.
我们哪也不去，布莱德利。
Now, we own this here land.
现在，我们拥有这片土地。
We pay taxes on it.
我们为此纳税。
Now, we don't bother nobody around here.
现在，我们不打扰这里的任何人。
We keep to ourselves.
我们保持沉默。
Now, colored folk just can't be running all the time.
现在，黑人不能总是逃跑啊。
There comes a time when you got to stand up...
有时候你得站起来…
and defend your rights.
捍卫你的权利。
Sylvester! Sylvester! Listen to me. And you listen.
西尔维斯特!西尔维斯特!听我说。你听我说。
Hold on there for a minute.
等一下。
We got to think about these here children.
我们得为这些孩子着想。
Oh, I am thinking about the children, preacher.
哦，我正在为这些孩子们考虑，牧师。
Now, you suppose they thinking about our children?
现在，你认为他们在考虑我们的孩子吗?
Mr. Mann.
曼恩先生。
If there be some trouble around here, sir,
如果这里有什么麻烦，先生，
we could sure use your help.
我们可能会需要你的帮助。
I just came from one war, friend.
我刚从战场上下来，朋友。
I ain't looking for another one.
我不想再找事了。
Let him go, Sylvester.
让他走，西尔维斯特。
For all we know,he could have been...
据我们所知，他可能是…
the one that done this thing.
作案的元凶。
They said it was... they said it was a stranger anyhow.
他们说那是…他们说那是个陌生人。
You're talking crazy now, preacher.
你在说什么胡话，牧师。
I wish y'all luck.
我祝愿大家都平安无事。
He ain't done nothing.
他什么都没有做。
What was that, Aunt Sarah?
那是怎么回事？萨拉阿姨？
Mr. Wright, would you kindly excuse us, sir?
赖特先生，你能善意地回避一下我们的谈话吗？
I seen his face.
我看见了那人的脸。
He was white as butter.
那是一个典型的白人脸。
What?
什么？
This what they teach you in the Army?
这就他们在军队教你做的吗？
Pack up and run when things get hot?
一碰上麻烦就收拾东西走人？
Thank God the Navy don't let in...
感谢上帝，海军不会让...
What? Go on and say it, Mr. Wright.
什么？接着说下去，赖特先生。
Thank God the Navy don't let in niggers.
谢天谢地，海军从没有让黑鬼参加进来。
I was going to say cowards.
我想说的是懦夫。
That's right.I got you figured, Mann.
那就对了。我知道你的打算，曼恩。
You one of them loud boys, big talk.
你也是个光说不练说大话的家伙。
Figure you can say anything to a white man...
你可以对白人说任何话...
as long as you start out saying,"With all due respect."
只要你以“恕我冒昧，”做开场白。
First sign of trouble, you duckin' your head running.
一有麻烦，你就躲得远远的。
What you going to do...
如果那些暴民来到这里...
when that mob come down the road?
你将怎么办？
You going to grab up your rifle,
你会拿起枪，
defend colored folk?
来保卫黑人吗？
What you care?
你在意什么？
Man does what he has to.Ain't that right?
人总得为所在意的事情而做点什么，对吧？
Just like a colored boy back from the war...
就像一个从战争中归来的黑人小伙子…
with a pocketful of money.
带着一口袋钱。
Ain't that right?
这合适吗？
You the massa of Rosewood, huh?
你是紫檀镇的乡绅吧？
Say, boy...
算是吧，孩子...
these people know me.
这里的人都认识我。
They trust me.
他们相信我。
How long you live here, Mr. Wright?
你住在这里多久了？赖特先生
Nine years.
九年了。
I been in Rosewood one night...
我只在紫檀镇住了一晚...
they asking me to stay.
他们要求我住下来。
Now, you pack up your truck...
现在，你收拾好你的卡车…
see who tries to stop you from leaving.
看看是谁试图阻止你离开。
You wasn't going to say nothing.
你不会什么都不说吧。
You was just going to leave me?
你就要离开我了吗？
Three, four weeks, this all blow over.
三，四个星期后，这一切都过去了。
Then I come back.
那时我再回来。
But I thought we...
但我以为我们…
Why, I didn't think you was just going to run off, is all.
我还以为你不是要跑掉呢。
Ain't you a soldier?
你难道不是一名士兵吗？
Scrappie.
斯卡比。
Them boys looking for a colored man...
那些男人在找一个黑人…
ain't nobody seen around here before.
以前没人在这附近见过的黑人。
Now, ain't no way in the world...
现在，这世界上没有办法…
one man got enough bullets for all them crackers.
一个人有足够的子弹对付他们。
Your own preacher ready to serve me up.
你的牧师准备把我送上祭台。
But if I stay,I'm asking to be hung.
但如果我留下，我就是在要求被绞死。
Look here.
看这儿。
They give me this for saving lives.
他们因为我救人而颁给我这个奖章。
Most important thing anybody ever give to me.
这是别人给予我的最重要的东西。
You keep it for me.
你替我保管它。
Hold on to it till I get back.
收好它，直到我回来。
Now, can you do that for me, darling?
现在，你能帮我个忙吗，亲爱的？
星期六，阿内特的生日。
Morning, Judge.
早上好，法官。
Multiple gunshot wounds.
多处枪伤。
Missing ear...
一只耳朵不见了...
fingers...
手指不全...
various other parts.
还有其他部分伤口。
By Jesus, your boys really got to this one, huh, Ellis?
天啊，你的人也真够可以的，对吧？艾利斯。
Yes, they did, sir.
是他们干的，先生。
Levy County is growing.
李维县正在扩展。
We need us a sheriff up here...
我们这里需要一个警长…
who can handle these nigger problems.
他要能处理这些黑鬼的事情。
Is that you, Ellis?
这会是你吗？艾利斯？
Now hold on, Judge.
等一下，法官。
Oh, I think I got everything under control now, Judge.
哦，我想现在一切都在掌控之中了，法官。
I hope so.
我希望如此。
We ain't talking about...
我们不是在说…
breaking up fights on Saturday night.
在周六晚上制止打架。
You can't control your colored,
你不能控制你治下的黑人，
we're going to replace you with someone who can.
我们就找个人来代替你。
Cause of death:
死因：
"Mischief at hands unknown..."
“恶作剧中失手致死...”
Write that down, Earl.
写下来，厄尔。
All right now!Get on in here!
全体注意！到这里来！
Fall in here, everybody!
大家来这里集合！
Now, hush up!
现在，都别废话！
Everybody, come on, now! Don't lollygag!
大家，快点! 别耽误功夫！
I want to give you a day off.
我今天要给你们放一天假。
What's that, Boots?
为了什么？布茨？
He says you got the day off.
他说，给你们一天的假。
All right!
好哇！
That colored boy what assaulted Fanny Taylor,
那个袭击范妮.泰勒的黑人男孩，
he's still out there somewhere.
他还逍遥法外。
So I'm gonna give you the day off...
所以我给你们放一天假...
so you can go help with the search.
这样你们可以协助搜查。
All I expect is...
我所希望的就是...
if you find him...
如果你们找到他...
well, you know what to do.
那你们，就自己看着办吧。
Oh, Lord, Auntie,
噢，上帝，阿姨，
they're likely to come in here and kill us all.
他们好像要闯到这里来杀我们了。
You got to tell them that man was white.
你得告诉他们那个人是个白人。
Child, you don't think...
孩子，你别想...
they going to listen to old Aunt Sarah?
他们会听萨拉老阿姨讲的话吗？
They'd just as soon as string me up...
他们只会马上把我绞死...
like they done Sam Carter.
就像他们对萨姆.卡特所干的。
You ain't never seen crackers act the way I know.
你从没见过那些坏蛋的行为，我知道。
When I was a little girl, about 7,
当我还是个大约7岁孩子时，
still on the Willowbrook plantation...
当时还在维罗布鲁克种植园...
old massa's son stole $20 out of the family chest...
老主人的儿子从家里的箱子里偷了20美元…
for a cockfight.
拿去斗鸡了。
Massa knew he took it.
主人知道是他儿子拿的。
As blue as Jesus' eyes, he knew.
就像他知道耶稣的眼睛是蓝色的。
But just the same...
但他还是...
he whipped my daddy half to death.
用鞭子把我爹抽了个半死不活。
It don't matter what man was beating on Fanny Taylor.
不管谁揍了范妮·泰勒。
Nigger.
黑人总是倒霉。
It's just another word for guilty.
只不过是有罪的另一种说法。
Here you go.
这是你的。
Thank you, Mr. Bryce.
谢谢你，布莱斯先生。
You're welcome.
不客气。
You're a nice gentleman.
你真是个大好人。
Look, why don't you get your peoples on board, Aunt Sarah?
为什么你不让你的人都上车呢？萨拉阿姨？
Take them up to Gainesville for a while.
带他们到盖恩斯维尔呆一阵。
Don't much like the looks of things around here.
我不太喜欢这里的情形。
Things been looking the same...
只要我还能记得住...
as long as I can remember, Mr. Bryce.
事情总是老样子，布莱斯先生。
You take care of yourself.
你自己多当心。
Take that.
接着。
Put it on the side there.
把它放在这边。
Board!
上车！
Sylvester?
西尔韦斯特？
- Go inside the depot, Mama.- Sylvester!
-你去仓库里。妈妈。 -西尔韦斯特！
Mama, it's all right.
妈妈，没事的。
Mama, go on.
妈妈，走啊。
Johnny.
约翰尼。
Sylvester!
西尔韦斯特！
Do you know the whereabouts of this Jesse Hunter?
你知道这个杰西·亨特的下落吗？
I do not.
我不知道。
You arrest that man who kill Sam Carter yet?
你们逮捕那个杀了山姆·卡特的人吗？
Don't you get uppity with me.
别对我这么傲慢。
I've come to warn you.
我来是警告你的。
There are some boys over there in Sumner...
萨姆纳那边有几个小伙子…
let on if they was you,
设想一下他们是你，
they wouldn't let sundown catch them around here.
他们不会等到太阳下山再来抓你的。
Well,they ain't me... sir.
但他们不是我...长官。
Why don't you be a good boy...
你为什么不做个好孩子…
and go visit some of your other relatives...
去拜访你的其他地方的亲戚…
for a little while, huh?
就在这几天，好吗？
I am trying to help you here.
我可是在帮你。
They're all over there right now getting all full of liquor...
他们现在都在那里喝得酩酊大醉…
and making nooses.
还在编绳套呢。
You hear me! Huh?
你就听我的话！好吗？
Sheriff...
治安官...
If you really want to help...
如果你真的想帮忙…
I appreciate it if you wouldn't allow...
就别让那帮小子来这儿，
them boys to come 'round here.
我会非常感激你的。
Now, I was born and raised in Rosewood.
我的出生和成长都在紫檀镇。
This here is my home.
这里是我的家。
And I'll be damned if I let anybody run me off it.
如果我被什么人赶走，那我也就死了。
Now, you can tell them boys that.
现在，你给那帮小子带个话。
Tell them your damn self.
你自己去告诉他们吧。
Damn colored fool.
该死的黑傻瓜。
Go home, Mama.
回家去，妈妈。
You're gonna have to settle your account...
你必须先把赊账结清...
before I can sell you the shells.
然后我再卖给你这些子弹。
Want me to settle the account?
想让我结清赊账？
That's right.
对了。
All right.
那好吧。
Go home, Jewel.
回家去，朱维尔。
Girl, you best get out of this store.
丫头，你最好离开这家店。
She belongs here.She belongs right here.
她属于这里，她就呆在这儿。
Do you see how you do my cousin?
你是都对我表妹干了些啥？
Get out this store right now, Jewel! Get!
快离开这家商店，朱维尔！快！
Can't you listen to nobody?
你就不能听听别人的话吗？
Sheriff give you good advice.Why ain't you leaving?
治安官给你忠告了。为啥你还不走？
I thought you a smart boy,Sylvester.
我认为你是聪明孩子，西尔维斯特。
I thought you a smart boy.
我想你脑子没病，孩子。
Here is your money,Mr. Wright.
这是你的钱，赖特先生。
That should settle my account.
应该够还清赊账了。
Sylvester...
西尔维斯特...
Dumb...
傻瓜...
Hurry up!
快走！
Here come them boys.
那些小伙子们来了。
They ain't got nothing.
他们什么都没找到。
What'd you find?
你们发现了什么？
Snakes and ticks.
竟是蛇和扁虱。
Them colored folks got to be hiding that nigger.
他的黑同胞一定把那黑鬼藏起来了。
What time is it,anyway?
现在几点了？
Well, let's see...by old Sam Carter.
好吧,让我们看看…老萨姆·卡特。
Bourbon time.
该喝波旁酒了。
I'll tell you, boys.
我跟你们说，小伙子们。
If anybody's hiding Jesse Hunter,
如果有人把杰西·亨特藏起来
my money's on Sylvester Carrier.
我把赌注押在西尔维斯特.凯利上。
That nigger,he hates us white folk.
那个黑鬼，他恨我们这些白人。
He does.
他是的。
You know,he's got a piano.
你们知道，他有架钢琴。
A nigger with a goddamn piano.
一个黑鬼居然他妈的还有钢琴。
I've been working all my life,
我工作了一辈子，
I ain't got a piano.
却没有钢琴。
You don't know how to play one.
你都不知道该怎么弹。
That ain't the point.
这不是重点。
Old man Cummer,up in that house of his,
坎默老伙计，就在他房里，
he's got a piano.
居然摆着一架钢琴。
That nigger's got one,and I don't.
黑鬼有，我却没有。
Now, how does that look?
这像话吗？
Yeah, and he's married to that white woman.
是啊，他还娶了那个白人女人。
Gertrude ain't white.
格特鲁德不是白人。
Hell, she look white.
见鬼，她看上去像白人。
Well, she ain't.
那她也不是。
She's half Negress,half-Seminole Indian.
她一半黑人，一半塞米诺印第安血统。
He says.
他说的。
It wouldn't surprise me if he was hiding that bastard.
我一点儿都不奇怪他藏了那个混蛋。
Hey, Judge.
嘿，法官大人。
I tell you, Duke.
我告诉你，杜克。
Can I get that bottle?
把那瓶给我喝一口吧？
Go ahead now,make a wish.
接下来，许个愿。
Blow the candles out.
吹蜡烛。
Open this one first, Arnett.Open that one.
先把这个打开，阿内特。打开。
Oh, yeah,that's nice, Mama.
哦，这个很好，妈妈。
Yeah, that's real nice.
这真的很好。
You're a man now.You need a suit of clothes.
你现在是男人了，该有一身合适的衣服了。
Arnett, open this one here and that one, too.
阿内特，把这个打开，那个也打开。
Sylvester got that one.
西尔维斯特送的那个。
Simmer down.Be quiet!
冷静一下，别出声！
Sylvester, come on out here now, boy.
西尔维斯特，你小子出来。
We want to talk to you.
俺们有话跟你说。
Bring that Jesse Hunter on out here with you.
你把杰西.亨特交出来。
Yeah, that's right.Bring that boy with you.
没错，把那小子带出来。
Jesse and Sylvester are probably sitting up in there.
杰西和希尔维斯特可能就在里面。
Shut up that damn dog.
别让那该死的狗叫了。
Sittin' up there now eating pork chops.
扔块排骨让它啃着。
Laughing at us all.
不把俺们当回事儿。
Goddamn, Duke!
该死，杜克！
Son of a...
王八蛋...
You had no call to do that.
你没必要这么做。
It's just a damn dog,Ellis.
只不过是一条该死的狗，艾利斯。
I'll have no more shooting.
不许再开枪了。
How you expect the boy to come out here...
你都把他的狗打死了...
if you're going to shoot his hound?
怎么能指望这小子出来?
Hell of a shot!
打得好！
Sylvester! You'd better get out here now.
西尔维斯特！你最好现在就出来。
Wait, Mama!Mama, hold on!
等一下，妈妈！别动！
Get out the window, Mama.
离开窗户，妈妈。
All right. I'm gonna go get the guns, Mama.
好吧，妈妈，我去拿枪。
You stay out the window.
你离开窗户。
No, Sylvester!
不，西尔维斯特！
Mama, just stay out the window.
妈妈，离开窗户。
Y'all children get down right now.
孩子们都给我趴下来。
Get down under the table right now.
现在全都躲到桌子底下去。
Scrappie, Gertie,you keep these kids down.
斯卡比，格蒂，你俩照顾好孩子们。
Big Baby, get down! Get down!
大宝贝，趴下！趴下！
We don't want to talk to you.We want to talk to your boy.
俺们不想跟你说。俺们想跟你儿子讲话。
Boys, why don't y'all go on home?
孩子们，你们为什么不在家呆着？
Miz Sarah, we want to talk to Sylvester.
萨拉女士，俺们想找西尔维斯特。
You get him out here!Right now!
你让他出来！马上！
Mr. Walker, my boy don't know nothing about this business.
沃克先生，我儿子对这事一无所知。
You let him tell us that.
你让他跟俺们讲。
Let Jesse Hunter tell us something.
让杰西·亨特跟俺们讲。
Boys, I know y'all.
孩子们，我认识你们每一个人。
I was midwife to more than half of you...
你们中有一半都是我接生的...
and some of your young ones.
还有你们自己的孩子。
Bring that boy out here now!
让那小子出来！
I done seen you come up from babies to now.
我看到你从婴儿成长到现在。
Ain't nothing going to come of this.
这事不该是这个样子的。
It don't make sense.
这没道理啊。
My Sylvester ain't had nothing to do with this mess.
我的希尔维斯特跟这事一点关系都没有。
We ain't never known no Jesse Hunter.
我们根本不认识什么杰西·亨特。
I was there with Miss Fanny.
我当时和范妮小姐在一起。
I seen the man's face as plain as day.
我在光天化日下看清了那人的脸。
And most of you mens know that that man was white!
他和你们大多数人一样，是个白人！
Who fired that shot?
谁开的枪？
You tell me right now.
你们回答我。
I told you no more shooting.
我说过了，不许再开枪。
Didn't I tell you that?
我没告诉过你们吗？
Aunt Sarah.
萨拉阿姨。
Poly, get back here!
波利，回来！
Shut up, Walker.
闭嘴，沃克。
Quit squealing like a stuck pig.
别像杀猪叫了。
I'll take this boy out myself.
我要亲自把这小子弄出来。
Damn you,get back here!
你该死，回来！
Pledge your souls to hell!
让你的灵魂下地狱吧！
Get back under there.Stay there! Stay down!
回到下面去。呆在那儿!趴着别动！
Get inside, son.Go on inside.
进屋去，儿子，进屋去。
Hold your fire!
停止射击！
Think we got him?
我们打中他了？
I don't know.
我不知道。
We gonna need more bullets.
俺们需要更多子弹。
You go and tell,
你快去，
tell the judge what happened here.
告诉法官这里发生的事情。
Go!
去！
Rest of y'all men, get back!Go on. Stay low.
其余的人退后！快，低着点儿走。
I'm right here.
我在这儿。
I'm right here, Mama.
我在这儿呢，妈妈。
Hold on!
挺住！
Hold on, OK, Mama? I'm right here.
妈妈坚持住，好吗？我就在这儿。
Don't try to talk,Mama, don't try to talk.
别说话，妈妈，别试着说话。
Don't...
别...
Don't let them s-s-surround you, baby.
别让他们包围你，宝贝。
It's all right.I won't, Mama.
没事了。我不会的，妈妈。
You just hold on, OK?
你只要挺住，行吗？
Mama, no, hold on.
妈妈，不，挺住。
Mama, hold on.
妈妈，挺住。
Y'all take what you need and no more!
你们全都要拿，已经没货了！
You hear me?
你们听见我说的了吗？
Y'all hear me?
你们都听见我说的了吗？
How am I going to be paid for all this?
怎么要我付出这么多?
You just keep track,that's all.
你只要记账就行了。
Y'all shoot Sylvester,Ellis?
你们都向西尔维斯特开枪了？艾利斯？
Don't know.
不太清楚。
They shot Aunt Sarah,though, John.
但他们还是射杀了萨拉阿姨，约翰。
Aunt Sarah!
萨拉阿姨！
What the hell's the matter with you, Ellis?
你这是怎么回事啊？艾利斯？
You let them come here and shoot an old woman?
你怎么让他们随便就打死一个老太太？
I didn't let them do that.
我没让他们这么做。
You call that upholding the law?
你就是这样维护法律的吗？
What kind of sheriff are you?
你算哪门子治安官啊？
Henry and Poly are dead.
亨利和波利死了。
Shot by them damn nigras.
被那该死的黑鬼打死的。
Where'd Sylvester get his ammunition, John?
约翰，西尔维斯特从哪儿搞来的弹药？
All right, come on.
没事了，来吧。
Come on. Hurry up! Hurry up!
来吧。快点！快点！
Come on! Come on!
来吧！来吧！
Take those babies,go hide in the woods.
带着这些孩子们躲进树林里。
Y'all babies going to get in the woods now.
孩子们，你们都到树林里去。
Go on!Go hide in the woods.
去吧！去树林里躲好。
Go on. Hurry up.Go hide in the woods.
快去树林里躲好。
Sylvester,I ain't leaving you.
西尔韦斯特，我不离开你。
Gertie, they gonna come back here...
葛蒂。那帮家伙还会回来的...
and try to kill all of us.
他们想杀了我们。
You and Scrappie got to go hide these children in the swamp.
你和斯卡比必须带孩子们躲进沼泽地里。
We can't take the babies out there. It's freezing!
我们不能让孩子们去那里。太冷了！
There ain't no place else.Go on and get out of here.
没有其它地方可去了。赶紧离开这里。
What about Aunt Sarah?
萨拉阿姨怎么办？
Just go on and get, girl!
只要离开就行，姑娘们！
Come on. Let's go.
来吧，我们走。
Gertie. I'll be there.
葛蒂，我回去找你们的。
You got to go. You got to go.
你们得走。你们得走。
Come on,Big Baby, get!
快去，大宝贝，走！
I can shoot,Sylvester.
我能开枪，西尔韦斯特。
Big Baby gonna shoot.
大宝贝要开枪。
All right.
好吧。
All right. Come on.
好吧。来吧。
How many are there in the house?
屋子里有多少人？
Sylvester, Jesse Hunter, James Carrier.
西尔韦斯特，詹姆斯.亨特，詹姆斯.凯利。
Probably that drifter.
也许还有那个流浪汉。
Yeah, Rodney. Listen.
好吧，罗德尼。听着。
You get together all the men you can find...
你把所有你能找到的男人聚在一起…
and you hightail it to Sumner.
你们速来萨姆纳。
Now, you make sure they bring rifles.
你要确保他们带着步枪。
What happened?
咋了？
Three dead white men is all.
有三个白人死了。
We done got ourselves a goddamn nigger revolt up here.
我们已经惹上了一场该死的黑鬼暴乱。
Hold your fire!
不要开枪！
There he is!
他又来了！
I think I got him!
我想我打中他了！
Hold your fire!
停火！
Goddamn you!
去你妈的！
Burn!
烧了它！
Light 'em up!
点燃它！
Some of y'all pick Henry and Poly up.
你们几个给亨利和波利收尸。
That Sylvester?
那是西尔韦斯特？
You son of a bitch!
你个王八蛋！
You want me to burn her, too?
你想让俺把她也烧了吗？
Couple y'all men,come over here.
过来几个人。
I want y'all to carry her down to the nigger graveyard.
我要你们把她抬到黑鬼墓地去。
Go on!
去吧！
I'll do it if you make me deputy.
如果你让俺当副警长，俺就去。
You're deputy now.
你现在就是副警长了。
Go on, pick her up.
去吧，给她入殓。
Hey, boys,I'm a deputy!
嘿，伙计们，俺现在是副警长了！
Hold on to that now. Grab the other side.
现在抬起这头。抓住那头。
Hold on, Bobby.Hold on.
等一下，波比。等一下。
This wasn't supposed to happen.
这是不应该发生的。
She worked in my damn house, Ellis.
她在我家工作，艾利斯。
Then give her a decent Christian burial, James.
那就给她一个体面的基督徒葬礼，詹姆斯。
You men, grab that end.
你们几个，抓住那头。
Damn, what did this old crow eat?
该死，这只老乌鸦都吃了什么？
Come on, lift it up!
来吧，抬起来！
Look out now! Look out!
小心脚下了！小心！
Aunt Sarah come in the morning.
萨拉阿姨早上会来的。
She clean up.
她来收拾房间。
Aunt Sarah ain't coming.
萨拉阿姨不来了。
No. You right.
是的，你说对了。
It's Sunday.
今儿是礼拜天。
Aunt Sarah ain't comin' no more.
萨拉阿姨不会再来了。
No more, no never.
永远不会再来了。
She's dead.
她死了。
Sylvester, too,dead as hell.
西尔韦斯特也进地狱了。
Sam Carter.
同萨姆.卡特一样。
Half of Rosewood's dead,
紫檀镇上一半的都死了，
and they ain't caught your nigger yet!
他们还没抓到强奸你的那个黑鬼！
Sarah...
萨拉...
Why they hurt that old woman?
他们为什么要伤害那个老大妈？
She never done nothin'to nobody.
她谁都没得罪过。
星期天
Y'all need to come on down here.
你们都过来一下。
We're gonna need some help.
俺们需要一些帮助。
Some colored beat and raped a white girl.
一些黑人在袭击并强奸一位白人妇女。
Yeah, them niggers need to be put in their place.
是啊，那些黑鬼应该被赶回他们来的地方。
Hell, they done forgot who they are.
见鬼，他们已经忘了他们是什么。
I'm gonna get me one.
俺也要去杀一个。
We're gonna string up all them darkies.
俺们要把那些黑人都吊起来。
Yes, we'll gather at the river
是的，我们齐聚河边
The beautiful,the beautiful river
这是一条美丽的河流
Gather with the saints at the river
汇集了圣徒们的河流
That flows...
那些花朵...
Y'all hear what happened in Rosewood?
你们都听说了紫檀镇上发生的事情了吧？
A colored boy killed four white men...
一个黑人小伙子杀死个白人男子...
and raped three white women.
还强奸了三名白人妇女。
Soon we'll reach the shining river
很快我们将到达闪光的河流
Soon our pilgrimage will cease
很快我们的朝拜就要结束
Soon our happy hearts will quiver
很快我们的心灵将会颤抖
With the melody of peace
带着此刻和平的旋律
Yes, we'll gather at the river
是的，我们齐聚河边
The beautiful,the beautiful river...
这条美丽的河流...
Right over there!
看那儿！
There he is!Get him!
就是他！抓住他！
On that horse!Give me my gun!
他骑着马！把枪给俺！
Jesse! You were better off on that chain gang, boy!
杰西！你最好就被锁着，小子！
There he is!
他在那里！
Let's go, boys!Come on! Get him!
我们上！小伙子们！来吧！抓住他！
Move it!
快撤！
Let's get out of here.
离开这儿。
Drop that gun!
把枪收起来了！
Get them horses out of here!
别把他们的马惊了！
Hey, you hold that horse down!
嘿，你拴住那匹马！
Now, get him on over there!
现在，把他弄到那边去！
Go on!
快去！
Oh, Ellis,let 'em run!
哦，艾利斯，让他们跑起来！
Let 'em run! Howdy-do!
让他们跑起来！都好吗！
Ooh, here come the parade.
我操，游行开始了。
Hey, listen up! Come on! Come on over here!
嘿，听着！过来！都到这边来！
Come on!
来吧！
15 niggers jumped us in the woods!
They was armed to the teeth!
他们都武装到了牙齿！
What? They bump you in the head?
怎么了？他们打肿你的头啦？
Sure enough did!
绝对是他们干的！
You go on and get them, then!
那你应该去把他们抓住！
Let's all get 'em!
让俺们一起去抓他们！
- Was it back there?- Back yonder.
-是在后面吗？-就在那后面。
Go now!
立刻出发！
Hey, Ellis, you got a phone call, Ellis.
嘿，艾利斯，有电话找你，艾利斯。
Not now, Earl!
现在不接，厄尔！
It's the governor, Ellis.
是州长打来的，艾利斯。
Pretty exciting stuff,huh, Ellis?
挺挺刺激吧？埃利斯？
Go right inside, Timothy.
进屋去，蒂莫西。
See the nigger?They got him.
看见那黑鬼了吗？他们抓到他了。
No. You've got to look and see.
不，你得睁眼看着这些。
You've got to remember this.
你要记住这些。
It's somethin' you've got to remember. Look.
这是你必须要记住的。看呀。
What? What?
怎么了？发生什么？
Mr. Wright,you have to hide me.
赖特先生，你得把我藏起来。
You are crazy.
你疯了。
I can't run.
我不能跑了。
Mr. Wright, I don't know where my boys are,
赖特先生，我不知道我的儿子在哪里，
and my baby girl is somewhere...
而我的宝贝女儿在...
in the woods.
树林里。
Mr. Wright...
赖特先生...
they killed my Virginia.
他们杀了我的弗吉尼亚。
They find you here,they'll burn my store.
如果他们发现你在这里，他们会烧了我的店。
You best run hide in the woods.
你最好也躲进树林里。
I can't run!
我跑不动！
I got shot through my side.
我中枪了。
I can pay you.
我可以给你付钱。
We'll put you in the back storeroom.
我们会把你放在后面的储藏室。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
We'll talk about that deed later, Bradley.
我们以后再谈钱的事，布拉德利。
God bless you,John Wright.
上帝保佑你，约翰.赖特。
Get some clean white rags, blanket.
拿些干净的白纱布，还有毯子。
Here they come.
他们来了。
What are you fellas doing in the road?
你们这帮家伙挡在路上作甚？
Hold steady, boys.
小子们，保持镇定。
You can back up right now!
你们现在可以后退了！
Move them trucks out!
把卡车挪开！
Come on!
快点儿！
You know what to do now.
你们知道该怎么做。
We got business to take care of!
我们还有事要做！
OK, now...
好了，现在...
Get them trucks out the road!
让他们把卡车驶离道路！
（阿拉楚阿县界）
- Turn around! - What are you boys doing?
-回去！ -你们这帮小子想干嘛？
（阿拉楚阿县界）
You need to get on out the road!
你们得闪开这条路！
We got business to take care of over there!
我们去那边有正经事要办！
Turn around!
回去！
You ain't bringing all this into our town.
你们不能把这些带到我们镇上来。
Oh, yeah, we are.
哦，好吧，我们就带了。
We're looking for a colored fugitive name of Jesse Hunter.
俺们在找一个叫杰西·亨特的有色人种逃犯。
Our coloreds are law-abiding folk!
我们这里的有色人种都是守法的！
Bronson don't want you.
我布朗森不需要你们。
Now turn around!
现在，掉头回去！
What are you all going down on us for?
为什么你们这么对待俺们？
Y'all gonna protect niggers?
你们都想庇护黑鬼吗？
That ain't no way to treat a white man!
你们不能这样对待白人！
Oh, hell,he ain't here.
该死，他不在这儿。
I'm gonna remember this!
俺会记住的！
Now, go on in there with them.
现在，和他们一起合影吧。
Ready?
预备？
Hey, Bobby!
嘿，波比！
Hey, we're goin' back over.You comin'?
嘿，俺们要去翻个遍。你来吗？
Yeah.I'll be along in a bit.
好的，我马上就来。
You save me some.
你们给我留点儿。
Them niggers, they runnin' like chicken, boy!
那些黑鬼，他们像小鸡一样逃了，小子！
They in the swamp now. We're gonna get 'em!
他们现躲在沼泽里。俺们会抓到他们的
Them's church bells.
教堂在敲钟。
My daddy's ringin' 'em.
我爸爸敲的。
Them crackers be ringin' them bells.
是那些坏蛋们敲的。
Now, you stay put, you hear?
现在，你们都呆好了，听见了吗？
No. That's my daddy in his church.
不。那是我爸爸在他的教堂里。
He tellin' us it's safe to come home.
他告诉我们现在可以回家了。
No, Denny, Lee Ruth...
不，丹尼，李.露丝...
Maybelle!
梅布尔！
Denny, come back here.
丹尼，回到这儿来。
Denny, no.Come back here.
丹尼，不。回到这儿来。
Bust it up, boys!
砸了它，小子们！
Bust it all up, now!
砸了它！马上！
Bust it all up!
把所有的都砸了！
Niggers!
黑鬼！
Come on. Git.
快走，孩子。
That's a fire, now,ain't it?
这把火怎么样？
Well, look,this come out perfect here.
你看，这样就好了。
13.
弄成13的形状
Then you pull that through there, see?
然后你把这头穿过这里，看见了吗？
Now, you pull on one of those.
现在，你拉一下。
That's perfect.That's good.
完成了，很好。
There you go.Pull tight.
就这样。拉紧。
There you go. That's good.
就这样，很好。
Now you've got it, boy.
现在你已经学会了，小子。
There's your noose.
这就是你的套索。
Now you make one.
现在你自己做一个。
Just like this one.
就像这个。
Oh, that's a good one.
哦，这个很好。
That's a good one.
这个很好。
Good boy.
好孩子。
Here. Use these and cover yourself up.
拿着，用这个把自己盖住。
It's all right.You're all right.
会没事的，你们全会没事的。
Scrappie, I'm freezing.
斯卡比，我都快冻死了。
Scrappie, I'm hungry.
斯卡比，我饿了。
Quiet, y'all!
你们都别出声！
They're gonna hear us.
他们会听见我们的。
They done killed everybody.
他们都被害了。
Aunt Sarah,Big Baby, Sylvester.
萨拉阿姨，大宝贝，西尔维斯特。
Scrappie.
斯卡比。
Look.
看。
It's more than 50 children hidin' around in the swamp,
有超过50个孩子躲在沼泽里
and they been out here all night...
他们在外面待了一整夜…
with nothing to eat,
没吃没穿，
and they're cryin',and they're freezin'.
他们一直在哭，他们都在受冻。
What we gonna do?What we gonna do?
我们怎么办？我们怎么办？
Y'all be quiet now.
你们现在必须安静。
Now, hush!
现在，安静下来！
Hush. Just hush.
安静。只有安静。
Stop fighting.
别去战斗。
Arnett...
阿内特...
Front and center.
你位置很重要。
Quit crying, Arnett.
别哭了，阿内特。
You ain't a little boy no more. You a man.
你已不再是小孩了。你是个男人。
Now, you see any tears in these eyes?
现在，你眼中不应再有泪水。
I need you to be strong.
我需要你坚强。
You're my lieutenant,understand?
你现在是我的副官，明白吗？
Yes, sir.
是的，长官。
Now, you gather up these women and children.
现在，把这些妇女和孩子集合起来。
You're gonna move deep into the swamp.
你们将进入沼泽深处。
All right.
好吧。
We gots to move.
我们要行动了。
Get up.
起来。
Come on. Get up.
快点。起来。
Come on. Move.
快点。出发。
Let's go. Move!
我们走，出发！
I knew you'd be back.
我就知道你是我们的依靠。
It's gonna be all right.
会没事的。
Let's move it.Get him up.
我们都走，帮他站起来。
Oh, he's bad.
哦，他有残疾。
He ain't gonna last out here.
他在这里撑不了多久的。
Emma, there ain't nothin'the matter with me.
艾玛，我没有什么问题。
- I can walk.- Daddy.
-我能走。-爸爸。
There ain't no place to go.
没有别的地方可去。
You come too late!
你来得太迟了!
All right, Timothy.Upstairs with the Turners.
好了，蒂莫西。和特纳一家上楼去。
Put him upstairs, too,in the front.
把他也带上楼，你带路。
That's enough.That's enough.
够了。够了。
Let's go. Upstairs.
我们上楼去。
Everyone upstairs!
每个人都上楼！
And clean this place up. Look at this.
把这里收拾干净。看看这摊。
Clean this up.
收拾干净。
Oh, my God!This is not happening.
哦,我的上帝!这是不该发生的。
What's the matter with you?
你怎么回事？
I know you don't...
我知道你不...
I know you don't like having colored folks in the house,
我知道你不喜欢黑人进这幢房子，
but this is a serious time.
但现在是危急时刻。
Is that what you think,
你真是这么想的吗？
that I don't like livin' here 'cause of the colored folks?
我就因为这些黑人，而不喜欢住在这里吗？
Is that what you think?
这就是你想法吗？
Well, what is it, Mary?
那你说是什么？玛丽？
I am caring for the colored folks in my home!
我刚还在照顾在我家的黑人！
It's my home, too.
这也是我的家。
I know.Yes, it's your home.
我知道，这是你的家。
You all treat me like a guest in my own house.
你在我自己的家里，总把我当成客人。
I got news for you,John Wright.
我告诉你，约翰·赖特。
Carol is dead.
卡罗尔已经去世了。
She's dead.She ain't comin' back,
她死了。她不会再回来了，
and I ain't leavin'.
而我也不会走的。
Oh, God!
噢，上帝！
Put me down.
放我下来。
Put me down!
放我下来！
Emma!
艾玛！
Put me down.
放我下来。
I hear you're hiding folk,Mr. Wright.
我听说你家在藏着什么人。赖特。
I need you to put away old James here.
我要你把老詹姆斯也藏起来。
You're misinformed.
你误会了。
You best take him.Go hide in the woods.
你最好带他走。躲到树林里去。
No. I don't want to go in there.
不。我不想去那儿。
Take him, and go hide in the swamp.
带他躲到沼泽里去。
I ain't gonna go in that house!
我不想进那幢房子！
- John Wright?- What?
-约翰.赖特？-什么？
I know what you been doin' with my daughter.
我知道你对我女儿做了什么。
What?
什么？
- Hush now. - I can run like you.
-现在需要冷静。-我能像你一样跑。
No, you can't.
不，你不行。
Now, you gonna get us killed.Just hush!
你这样会让我们都被杀的。你要冷静！
Come on, Mr. Wright.
算了吧，赖特先生。
You the massa around here.
你是这里的乡绅。
I ain't a massa of nothin'.
我算个狗屁乡绅。
You best git while you can.
你们最好趁早离开。
- What's the matter, Mr. Wright? - Git!
-怎么了？赖特先生？-快走！
Don't he owe you enough to save his life?
难道他不值得你救吗？
You son of a bitch.
你个王八蛋，
How much it take for you to hide this man?
要付你多少钱？你才愿意藏下这个人？
$10? 15?
How about 60, goddamn 50?
I'm gonna blow your head off!
我要打爆你的脑袋！
This man's life worth one acre of land?
这人的一条命还不值你的一英亩地？
Hide the man, John,for God's sake.
收留他吧，约翰，看在上帝的份上。
Let him in.
让他进来。
Come on.
来吧。
快走。
No, Mama.
不，妈妈。
Come on, baby.
快走，宝贝。
No, Mama. It's all right.You go on.
不,妈妈。没关系。你继续。
Go, Mama! I'm all right.
你去，妈妈！我没事的。
I can't go in there, Mama! Take care of Papa.
我不能进那幢房子，妈妈！照顾好爸爸。
Come on!
快来！
Come on, now. Git!
快点儿，块！
Go.
去吧。
I'll be all right, Mama.
我会没事的，妈妈。
What's the problem, boys? What's the matter?
有什么问题吗？小伙子们？怎么回事啊？
We want James Carrier.
我们要詹姆斯.凯利。
Right now.
快点。
Well, I ain't seen him.Hell, I ain't seen nobody.
我没见过他，我这儿压根儿就没人。
Damn it, John.
该死的，约翰。
We caught his daughter.
俺们抓住了他的女儿。
We know he's here!
俺们知道他在这里！
What did y'all peckerwoods do to her?
你们这些乡巴佬对她做了什么
Where's she at, damn it?
该死的，她在哪儿？
Where's she at, Ellis?
她在哪儿，艾利斯？
Come on now!It's her daddy we after!
得了吧! 我们要找的是她爸爸！
Explain to me why you want to lynch a cripple.
告诉我你为什么要对一个瘸子动私刑。
We ain't lynchin' nobody don't need to be lynched, John.
俺们不会对任何人用私刑，也不需要用私刑，约翰。
I just don't see no sense in it.
我只是觉得这没什么意义。
John, James Carrier was in that house...
约翰，詹姆斯·凯利在那房子里…
with Sylvester and Jesse Hunter!
还有西尔韦斯特和杰西.亨特！
Yeah. We just want to ask him a few questions, John.
是的。我们只是想问他几个问题，约翰。
That's all.
仅此而已。
Well, that's all fine,but I ain't got him.
那很好，但他不在我这里。
All right, boys!
行了，孩子们！
Stay back!
退后！
You get off my porch!Get off my...
你们滚出我家门廊! 滚出我的…
Don't you come near!
你胆敢再上前一步！
Simmer down!
别发火！
Johnny,you want these boys...
约翰尼，你想让这些小伙子们...
to go through your wife and children?
搜查你的妻子和孩子们吗？
Is that what you want?
难道你想要这样？
Come on! Bring him out!
算了吧！你就把他叫出来吧！
We will! That's what we're gonna do!
我们会的！这就是我们要做的！
You give me your word,
你向我保证，
all you want to do is question him? Yes?
你们就是想盘问他吗？是吗？
That's more like it!
这才像话！
Y'all wait here.
你们都等在这里。
Get that nigger out here!
把那个黑鬼带到这儿来！
He was in the house the whole time.
他一直在房子里。
Get that damn nigger!
带那该死的黑鬼出来！
John!
约翰！
John, where are you going?
约翰，你要去哪里？
You're not going to let those people have him?
你不能让那些人带走他吧？
Mary, please.
玛丽，请别这样。
If I don't, they'll come in here and shoot us all.
如果我不这么做，他们会进来把我们都杀了。
They just want to ask him some questions.
他们只是想问他一些问题。
I'll be with him to make sure they don't do more than that.
我会和他在一起，确保他们不会做更过分的事。
I'll be with him.
我陪他一起。
Now, James...
现在，詹姆斯...
We got old Sarah over here, resting her soul.
我们把老萨拉阿姨带到这里，愿她灵魂安息。
If you don't tell us where this Jesse boy is,
如果你不告诉我们杰西在哪，
we're gonna have to put you in there with her.
我们得把你和她一起埋进去。
It's a big box!
这是口大棺材！
Why ain't my sister buried?
为什么我的姐姐还不下葬？
'Cause you ain't buried her yet.
因为你没有给她下葬。
Dig a hole,nigger.
挖个坑，黑鬼。
I ain't got but one good arm.
我只有一只胳膊能用。
We ain't got but one good shovel.
俺们也只有一把好铲子。
Come on. Get up here,you old crow,
来吧。就在这儿挖，你这个老乌鸦
and dig your own hole.
把你自己的坑也挖了。
Come on!
快点儿！
Show us what you're made of.
让俺们看看你的本事。
Come on! Let's go!
来吧！我们干吧！
Grab that shovel.Let me see what you can do.
拿起那把铲子，让俺看看你有多能干。
Get him goin'!
让他干完活！
Whoa! He's eager, ain't he?
呜哇！他很卖力，对吧？
James, stop it.
詹姆斯，住手。
Just trying to help him put that shovel in the ground.
俺只是想帮他拿起地上的铁锹。
James, listen here.
詹姆斯，听我说。
I want you to tell these boys where Jesse Hunter is.
你要告诉是我，杰西.亨特在哪里。
He was in that house with you, wasn't he?
他是不是和你在房子里？
Now, tell me, hear me? Listen up.
现在，告诉我？听清楚了？
James, you tell them something, hmm?
詹姆斯，你跟他们说点什么
James, look at me!
詹姆斯，看着我！
You tell them something,for God's sake.
看在上帝的份儿上，你就说吧。
I'm pleading to you.
我恳求你。
Sheriff,I can't lie to you.
治安官，我不能对你撒谎。
I ain't never met the man.
我从未看见那个人。
Fair enough.
说得好。
Stop! Duke!
住手！杜克！
God! What's the matter with you, Duke?
上帝！你怎么回事？杜克？
What the hell is the matter with you?
你到底是怎么回事？
Oh, hush up, John.
哦，安静，约翰。
You done went and turned nigger lover on us.
你的黑鬼情人让你背叛了俺们。
Ever since your wife passed away,
自从你的前妻过世后，
you ain't been the same.
你就和以前不一样了。
I'm goin' home, y'all.
俺要回家了，各位。
Nigger lover, my ass!
让黑鬼情人舔俺的屁股吧！
You stupid piece of white trash!
你这个愚蠢的白人垃圾！
What did you call me?
你管俺叫什么？
Don't you nigger lover me,you white trash!
难道你没有黑鬼情人，你个白色垃圾！
Come on!
来吧！
Think of who you are.Think of who you are.
想想你是谁。想想你是谁。
Think of what you're saying.
想想你刚才说的。
Don't do this.
别再这样了。
Nigger lover.
黑鬼的情人。
Nigger lover!
黑鬼的情人！
Whose side you on,Johnny Wright?
你站在哪一边？约翰尼.赖特？
Don't even care a white man got shot!
我才不在乎再一个白人中枪！
You forgetting who you are, Johnny?
你忘了自己是谁了，约翰尼？
Go home, Johnny.
回家去,约翰尼。
You go home right now.
你马上回家。
You got the money that man owes me?
你来还那人欠我的钱吗？
Y'all gonna pay me for all the money I'm losing?
你们要把我损失的钱还给我吗？
Hell, no!
见鬼去，不！
Killin' all of my customers,
你们把我的主顾都给杀了，
runnin' 'em off.
都被赶走了。
You watch who you call white trash, boy!
我管谁叫白色垃圾，小子！
That's right.
没错。
Just 'cause you rich off nigger money,
就因为你靠黑鬼的钱发财，
you think you better than all the rest of us?
你就以为你比我们都强吗?
That's right!
没错！
You get all the money in Florida, Johnny Wright,
你即使把全佛罗里达的钱都赚走了，约翰尼，
you still ain't nothin'...
你还是什么都不是...
but a dirt-floor cracker!
就是一个肮脏的地板下的臭虫！
Shopkeeper!
小店主！
星期一
Hey, now, wake up.
嘿，快醒醒。
Come on.
起来。
Come on. We got to go.Time to wake up.
起来。我们得走了。该醒醒了。
We're going to go this way.
我们走这条路。
Gertie, where are we going?
葛蒂，我们要去哪里？
Keep quiet.
保持安静。
We're going to go this way.
我们走这条路。
I ain't got no bullets.
我没有子弹了。
Share!
要分享！
Hey, y'all be quiet!
嘿，你们都别出声！
Y'all be quiet.
你们要安静。
Want them crackers to hear you?
你们想让那坏蛋们听见你们吗？
Bring the train to the old road near Kelly's pond.
我去把火车引领到凯利家池塘附近的旧铁路上。
Get there, listen for the engine whistle.
你们想办法到那里，注意火车开动声。
That's on the other side of Sumner, Mr. Wright.
那可是在萨姆纳镇的另一头，赖特先生。
How we gonna do that?
我们怎么到那里？
You're askin' us to take these children...
你要我们带着这些孩子...
through all them crackers?
在那些坏蛋们眼皮底下通过？
Can't stop near Rosewood.It's Kelly's pond or nowhere.
不能再靠近紫檀镇了。只能在凯利池塘停车了。
No men on the train. That's the plan.
没人会注意那辆火车。这是计划好的。
How we know we can trust you, Mr. Wright?
我们怎么知道可以信任你，赖特先生?
Got no choice.
别无选择。
In the trenches now.
现在就是在战壕里。
8:00. That's three hours.
晚上8点。还有3个小时。
Get these folks there.
把这些乡亲们送到那里。
I'll bring the train.
我去把火车引领来。
If you're lying,I'm comin' for ya.
如果你撒谎，我饶不过你。
Soldier, if I'm lying,you're dead.
士兵，如果我骗了你，你现在已经死了。
Yes, sir.
是的，长官。
We agreed about the men?
我们是同一战线的。
Yes, sir.
是的，长官。
That includes you.
那也包括你。
Johnny, we just went through there this morning.
约翰尼，我们今天上午已经去过那里了，
It ain't nothin' but ashes and smoke.
它到处是灰烬和浓烟。
Town's in purgatory.
整个镇子就像是炼狱。
Billy, it's a real simple thing,we do it right.
比利，很显然，我们在行正义之事。
They got boys on all the bridges,
他们派人在所有的桥上，
all the main roads lookin' for colored men.
所有的主干道上寻找黑人。
We go in at night,round back to Sumner,
我们晚上进去，绕回萨姆纳，
pick up the women and children,
接上妇女和孩子，
sweep them off to Gainesville.
把他们带到盖恩斯维尔去。
He's talkin' about Sumner!
他在说萨姆纳!
That's where the whole damn thing started!
整件事就是从那里开始的!
You're askin' us to risk our engine, Johnny!
你让我们拿机车冒险，约翰尼！
Who are you Bryce brothers,
你以为是谁?布莱斯兄弟，
a couple of rich boys playin' on your train?
难道几个富家小孩子上你的火车玩吗？
To hell with you.
你见鬼去吧。
You boys puffin' around the countryside...
你的孩子们可以走在乡间小路上...
wavin' and tootin' your whistle?
向你挥手，向你吹口哨。
To hell with you!
见鬼去吧你！
These are real folks dyin',
这些乡亲们正在死去，
women and children ain't done nothin' wrong to no soul.
他们的女人和孩子能有什么错。
That ain't fair, Johnny!
这不公平，约翰尼！
Don't talk to me about fair, Billy!
别跟我谈什么公平，比利！
They shot Sarah Carrier down like a dog on her own porch!
他们在莎拉·凯利家的门廊上像杀狗一样把她打死了!
I ain't asking you to risk your train!
我不是让你拿火车冒险!
I'm asking you to risk your asses!
我是在让你们冒生命危险!
Think they gonna let the women and children through?
你觉得他们会让女人和孩子通过吗?
I don't know.
我不知道。
Wait, wait.
等等。
Stay here.
呆在这里。
Damn.
该死。
Let's go. We gotta move.
快点。我们必须得走了。
How far out are we?
我们还要走多远？
About 40 minutes.
大约要40分钟。
Can't we move this thing any faster?
我们就不能再快一点儿吗？
Push that throttle, J.B.
推动那个油门，J.B.
Don't you be telling us how to run our train, Johnny.
别告诉我们该怎么开火车，约翰尼。
We gotta take it easy on her.She ain't been acting right.
我们得悠着点。这辆车状况不太好。
Oh, she ain't?
哦，不会出故障吧？
You boys been treating this train like a little sister...
你们对待它就像对你们的姐妹...
since I known you.Get her moving.
自从我认识你们以来。让这车跑快点。
She can't handle it!
它会受不了的！
Get this son of a bitch moving.
加快速度，
J.B., give her a little.
J.B.给它加点儿速度。
Feel better?
行了吧？
Yeah.
是的。
I feel better.
我感觉好多了。
I'm tired.
我累了。
I don't feel like going.
我不想再走了。
Hush up.
安静。
Hush up, be quiet.
安静，别出声。
That truck coming, boys.
卡车来了，小伙子们。
Watch out, now.
现在都注意了。
Watch yourself.
小心点。
Get on up.
上去。
Come on.
过来。
Wait, wait.
等等。
Might as well come look.
最好来看一眼。
Make room for my boy here.
让一下，让这孩子看一下，
Why you cryin', boy?
你哭什么？小子。
There's babies in there.
里面还有婴儿。
A nigger is a nigger, boy.None of us like it.
黑鬼就是黑鬼，儿子，我们没人喜欢他们。
God made the world the way it is,
上帝创造了这个世界，
and we just got to live in it.
而只有我们能生活在其中。
You get as old as I am,you become a man...
当你像我这么大的时候，要当一个男人...
you're gonna learn a lot of things.
你会学到很多东西。
A nigger is a nigger, boy.
黑人就是黑人，小子。
That's the way.
就是那样。
You understand me,Emmett?
你懂我的话吗？艾美特？
You understand me?
你理解我吗？
She's overheating!
它都发烫了！
Damn it!
该死的！
Damn it, I told you!
该死的，我跟你说过！
We're stopping,we're stopping!
我们开不动了，我们停住了！
We can't stop.No, no.
我们不能停。不，不。
Don't you get it?
你难道不知道吗？
你难道不懂吗？
We are stopped!
我们停住了！
We can't go anywhere!
我们哪儿都去不了！
It's your fault!
这都怪你！
Your fault!
怪你！
Goddamn counterbalance pin!
该死的平衡栓！
Damn it!
该死的！
J.B., leave him alone.You gotta check the engine.
J.B.,离他远点。你得检查引擎。
Don't you heathens touch my porch.
你们这些异教徒不许碰我的门廊。
Step aside.
闪开。
We hear you're hiding niggers in here.
俺们听说你这里藏着黑鬼，
Turn around, Earl, before I send us both to damnation.
转过身去，厄尔，在我把我们都送进地狱之前。
Jesus Christ, Mary.
上帝，玛丽。
That damn thing ain't loaded anyway.
反正那玩意也没上子弹。
Oh, yes, it is.
哦，是的，就是。
You got any niggers in there, Mary?
里面有黑鬼吗，玛丽？
Willing to kill a white woman to find out, Bobby?
你想杀了一个白人妇女而进去查看吗？波比？
Now turn around and get home.
现在你们掉头，回家。
Get on, get!
想试试，来！
Come on, Earl.Ain't no niggers around here.
算了吧，厄尔。附近也没看见什么黑鬼。
Come on, y'all.
大家都撤。
Come on, now.
现在，走吧。
You men best hope the Lord feels merciful come Judgment Day.
你们最好祈祷在审判日到来时上帝会发发善心。
Hush.
安静。
Everybody front and center.
所有人都列队。
Lieutenant.
副官。
Where's Arnett?
阿内特呢？
He gone.
他不见了。
Where's Minnie?
明妮在哪里？
Stay put.
呆着别动。
What y'all boys need to get this engine running again?
你们需要什么才能让引擎重新运转起来？
Somethin' we ain't got.
有些东西我们没有。
Counterbalance pin.
平衡栓，
What is a counterbalance pin?
什么是平衡销？
Oh, it ain't nothin'.
哦，也不算什么。
Piece of metal about this long.
就是一根大概这么长的铁棍。
Be quiet. Minnie, be quiet.
安静。明妮，安静。
All right, y'all men, listen up.Let's call it a night.
好了，伙计们，听好了。今晚就到此为止吧。
Bobby, Earl, give me a hand.Get these men out of here.
鲍比，厄尔，帮俺个忙。让这些人出去一下。
Y'all go home.
你们回家吧。
Get these men out of here.Go on.
把这些人带出去。继续。
No more camping out in my town! You hear me?
不许在我们镇上露营!你听到我说的吗?
Hush, y'all, hush!
安静，你们都安静！
All right,I see you in there.
好了，俺好像看到他了。
What you up to, Duke? What do you see?
你打算干什么？杜克？你看见了什么？
Hold still, now. Right up against that tree, y'all.
现在不要动。就靠在那棵树上。
Go get him.
去抓住他。
Minnie.Minnie's back.
明妮。明妮回来了。
Where you been?
你去哪儿了？
What...
怎么了...
He gonna get killed looking for you.
他会因为找你而送命的。
Show you to rape my wife.
让你强奸我老婆。
Put him up!
把他吊起来！
Simmer down, y'all!
你们都消消气！
I had a nice quiet town here,
本来我这个镇子好好的，
but you put an end to that,didn't you, boy?
你一来就全完了，对吧？小子？
Wasn't no colored boy...
黑人男孩…
had nothin do to with what happened there.
…跟那里发生的事没有任何关系。
Shut up.
闭嘴。
Shut up, Jesse.
闭嘴，杰西。
That ain't my name.
那不是我的名字。
Clear a path.
让开一条道。
Get back, get back.
退后，退后。
Run the nigger up.
把那黑鬼吊起来。
Ha, damn you!
哈，你个该死的！
Come on,you stupid horse!
快点，你个愚蠢的马！
Just shoot the damn horse.
杀了那匹该死的马。
Booker T., go!
布克.T.快跑！
Goddamn.
该死的。
That is one strong buck.
这家伙很结实。
Why won't he die?
为什么他还不死？
He gonna die, he gonna die.His neck ain't that thick.
他就要死了。他会死的。他的脖子没那么结实。
Oh, he'll die,
哦，他会死的，
only he probably didn't have nothing to do with it.
只是有可能，他什么都没做，
Well, truth be told,none of 'em did.
也许，真相会揭示出他们中谁也没做。
What the hell does that mean, Ellis?
你他妈这是什么意思？艾利斯？
It means, James,
就是说，詹姆斯，
that you know as well as I do...
你我心里都清楚...
what Fanny'd been doing lunch times.
范妮总是在吃午饭时间做什么勾当。
Some of y'all know better than others!
你们中有些人甚至更清楚！
That's right.
没错。
Should have never listened to her.
就不该听她的胡说八道。
That woman's a wildcat.
那个女人是个靠不住的女人。
Booker T.!
布克.T!
Shoot him!
开枪！
Sorry I had to say it that way, James,
原谅我这么说，詹姆斯，
but this thing's gone far enough.
但这件事情已经闹得够严重了。
Fanny lied...
范妮在说谎...
to you, to me,the whole damn town.
对你，对我，对整个镇子。
Deep down, I don't think I believed her from the start.
说实在的，我从一开始就有点儿不相信她。
If that's how you feel,
如果她如你所说，
why'd you take her word for this, Ellis?
为什么你还把她说的当成证言？艾利斯？
What choice I got, huh?
我能有什么选择？呃？
I am the sheriff.
我是治安官。
Damn.
该死。
My badge.
我的警徽呢。
What's gonna keep it in place?
怎么能让它保持正常运行？
Prayer.
祈祷。
Move it!
快跑！
Come on, move!
快点，跑啊！
Get on board, get on board,get on board.
快上车，上车，上车！
Get 'em on,get 'em on!
大家都上车，大家都上车！
Come on, move.
快点儿。
Get on, get on!
上去，上去！
Come on. We ain't gonna sit on the track all night.
快点，我们可不会整晚在铁道上等你们。
Move!
快！
Get them on!
把他们拉上去！
Quickly!
快点儿！
Let's go!
我们走！
Let's go. Let's get the hell out of here.
快走，快离开这鬼地方。
You can't come on! You can't come on!
你不能上来！你不能上来！
Let me on this train!
我要搭上这列火车！
I said get down!
我说了，下去！
If they find men on this train,they'll kill everyone!
如果他们发现这列火车有成年男人，他们会杀了所有的人！
Get off!
滚开！
Please!
救命啊！
Stop the train!
把火车停下吧！
Get back.If they find men on this train,
退后。如果他们发现火车上有男人，
they'll kill all the women and children!
他们会杀了所有的女人和孩子!
You can't come on here!
你们不能上这趟列车！
No!
不！
Get down,get down!
趴下，趴下！
What the hell you doing?
你他妈在干什么？
This is a war!We're in the trenches!
这是战争！我们在同一战壕里！
Jesus Christ!
上帝啊！
Come on, girl.
加大马力，铁丫头。
Child, stay down.Stay down.
孩子，趴着。趴着。
Y'all can get up now.
你们可以起身了。
You can't go, Mann.You just can't.
你不能走。曼恩。就不走。
Don't leave us, Mann.
别离开我们，曼恩。
Please don't leave us.
请不要离开我们。
Hush now.
都别说了！
Y'all gonna be safe.
你们会很安全的。
Scrappie in charge from here on in.
斯卡比负责这里的一切。
Arnett, you're a lieutenant.You help her out.
阿内特，你还是副官。你协助她。
Take these children inside.
把这些孩子带进去。
Y'all gonna be all right.
你们会没事的。
That's Booker T.!
那是布克.T!
Mr. Mann, who is that riding your horse?
曼恩先生，骑你马的是谁?
It's Sylvester.
是西尔维斯特。
Uncle Sylvester made it.All right! He made it.
西尔维斯特叔叔。太好了，他没死。
Sylvester,how you doing?
西尔维斯特，你怎么会这样？
Uncle Sylvester's alive.
西尔维斯特叔叔还活着。
I ain't got all night, Mann.
我不能就这样等你整晚，曼恩。
Gertie, y'all get to Cousin Wilma in Gainesville.
葛蒂，你们去找盖恩斯维尔的威尔玛表姐。
Come on.
快来。
I'll be waiting for you in Gainesville.
我在盖恩斯维尔等着你。
Won't be waiting long.
不会让你等太久的。
How'd you get out?
你是怎么脱身的？
They carried me...
他们载着我...
in my mama's coffin.
我藏在我妈的棺材里。
They were here.
他们来过这里了。
A mob.
一群暴民。
They tried to get in.
他们想闯进来。
What happened?
发生了什么？
Mom scared 'em off.
妈妈把他们吓唬跑了。
Boys.
儿子们。
星期二
Come here!Get up! Get up!
醒醒！起来！起来！
Liar!
骗子！
Damn you, woman!
该死的臭娘儿们！
Where you going, boy?
你要去哪儿？小子？
You little crab.
你个小螃蟹。
You eat my food,then you walk away sideways.
俺喂你吃的，然后你就横着走。
Emmett!
艾默特！
Emmett, come on back in the house, boy.
艾默特，回到房子里来，孩子。
L... I'm sick.
俺...俺很难受。
My hands is hurting me bad.
俺的手疼得厉害。
I need your help,and my back...
俺需要你的帮助，还有俺的后背...
Emmett, I don't mean to be hard on you, boy.
埃米特，俺不想对你太苛刻，孩子。
I just want what's best for you.
俺只是想为你好。
I want to learn you how to live in the world.
俺想让你学会，如何生活在这个世界上。
I hate you!
我恨你！
You ain't no man!
你不是个人！
I don't know what you are, Daddy.
我都不知道你算哪门子父亲。
Emmett, you come back... Emmett.
艾默特，你回来...艾默特。
Don't you walk away.Come on here, boy.
别走了。回来，孩子。
Emmett, come on back in here.
艾默特，回到这里来。
Which way are you headed?
你要去哪里？
Same as you, friend.Going to catch that train.
和你一起去追那辆火车。
J.布莱德利有5英亩土地出售
在大屠杀过后70年的1993年，佛罗里达州众议院给予当时在紫檀镇的受害家庭
以抚恤金，首当其冲的就是费尔莫娜的儿子，阿内特医生。
这个案件的诉讼成功很大程度上得益于几位幸存者的庭上宣誓证词，他们就是
事件发生时的儿童，还有就是一位站在受害者的立场上的白人公民的书面证言。
按照佛罗里达州官方公布，在紫檀镇大屠杀的死亡人数是八名
...两名白人，六名黑人。
据至今还活在世上的为数不多的幸存者回忆，死亡人数应该有四十到一百五十人，
其中大部分为非洲裔美国人。
翻译：hardstick 校订：hardstick